What is your emergency?
My mom killed herself.
Okay,
what is the address of the emergency?
Southwest 22nd Place,
St.
Okay,
is she breathing?
No,
she's not.
She's not breathing?
She's not.
Oh my God.
I'm going to cut it.
She cut her neck.
I don't know.
I think this is a murder.
I think.
Her hands are tied.
Her hands are tied?
It's so scary now.
Okay.
Oh my
God. I hope her house is going to run us through.
What did you find?
I found a broken door.
And you found a broken door where?
On the guest room.
Justin?
What the fuck?
Where is my knife?
This is dirty.
Okay,
were you saying something about a knife,
Justin?
Yeah,
I just found a knife near my front door.
I'm just walking all around my house right now.
Okay,
just don't touch anything.
Cold,
cold eyes upon me they stare
People all around me
And they're all in fear
They don't seem to want me
But they won't admit
I must be some kind of creature If they haven't been
Having a hard time
In this crazy town
There's no love to be found.
This morning,
a murder mystery in a quiet,
gated community.
Jill Halliburton Sue found dead in her bathtub.
Jill Sue is related to the Halliburton Oil Empire.
her great uncle founded the company.
Police say her husband,
Dr.
Nan Yao Su,
was at work Monday morning and told them when he couldn't see his home surveillance cameras on his computer,
he called his oldest son to check on the house.
An autopsy now confirms the woman was murdered,
but how and why is still unclear.
And by all accounts,
all seemed normal before this incident.
In fact,
the victim had just gotten back from a vacation.
to Malaysia.
And this morning police say they still don't have a suspect or even a person of interest and they certainly haven't revealed any possible motive for this murder.
At this time this is a very active investigation.
We did find a door that was broken.
Suggesting the house could have been broken into.
A room reportedly ransacked.
Police are now canvassing that gated neighborhood even diving into nearby canal.
On six,
police make an arrest in the death of a woman whose body was found last week inside a gated community in Davie.
And the suspect is 20 years old.
Police say he may have gotten spooked while trying to rob her.
His name is Deontay Reziles.
He's being booked into the Broward County Jail as we speak.
Investigators say it appears Reziles was burglarizing the home and didn't think anyone was inside.
Detectives say he has a history of breaking into high-end homes.
Why he chose Sue's residence is still unclear.
Cops don't know of any connection between him and the family.
They're also trying to figure out how he got into the gated neighborhood and got away undetected.
Detectives won't say what led them to Rosales,
but sources tell Local 10 it was forensic evidence discovered at the murder scene.
His DNA was present and it was unexplainable.
The police had no idea.
The Davie Police Department had no idea who Deontay Rosales was.
They had no reason to suspect him.
In fact,
they didn't suspect him until...
His DNA popped up at the scene.
I didn't believe,
I didn't think it was real,
Sam.
I thought I was sleeping.
When I was in the investigation room,
I'm biting inside my mouth because I'm feeling like this is not real.
Then they told me what's what,
what happened.
Then they told me what I'm being charged with.
Sam,
my whole life just fell out of my feet.
You're going to be here a little bit longer.
We're going to complete some paperwork and you're going to be charged with first degree murder.
Well first...
First we murder,
okay?
What am I being charged with first we murder for?
You know,
you can't talk here so...
What?
I'm gonna...
I'm gonna fix this.
When I realized it was real,
Sam,
was when they stripped me of all my clothes.
They took all my clothes and then they took pictures and all that other stuff.
And then
I was just like,
I thought it was over.
I was like,
man,
my whole life going down the drain now.
It's been two weeks and,
you know,
we don't get all of the information and all of the discovery as of yet.
They just give us a body and they just give us sort of like,
okay,
this is why he was arrested and this is what he was arrested for.
So there's not a lot of information that's coming in right now,
but the only thing that we know is that they're saying DNA puts our guy there.
Mr.
Reziles becomes the suspect because his DNA is found on two items.
One is a knife that's found on the front porch.
And ironically,
I...
I believe the knife was matched to a knife collection that the son had in his bedroom.
And the other is a green belt that's found just inside the front door on a rug there.
Mr.
Rizal's DNA profile was in the system from an earlier case that he had had.
And of course,
when they linked it up with him,
they went and arrested him.
It's not a lot of DNA that you would expect in a murder case to be there.
Especially one that is so bloody and gruesome and seems like someone that was,
you know,
still able to fight back and things like that.
It's very minimal DNA,
but that's the strongest evidence against Deontay that they have.
So on September 7th of 2014,
Nanyo Su and his wife Jill Halliburton came back from Malaysia after being there for two weeks.
On that day,
their son Justin Su picked them up from the airport about four...
15,
4.30 in the afternoon and drove them back home.
You know,
they were up most of the night because they were jet lagged.
And
Justin stated that he didn't go to bed until about 2 o'clock and his parents were still up because of the jet lag.
Now,
Justin had to go to work and he was working at Broward Community College,
which was directly across the street from where his father was working at the University of Florida at Davie Campus.
So he leaves the house about 9.45 and the video camera,
pictures.
from the guard gate,
has him leaving at that time.
Daniel,
at some point in the morning,
decides that he wants to go to work.
He gets up,
he then leaves for work sometime around 11.30.
His work is about eight or nine miles away at the University of Florida.
When he gets to the office,
sometime about 45 minutes into his job,
he claims that he went on the computer to the drop cam access.
Just to look and see what was going on in the house.
That's the time I saw a cooking on,
and I saw this figure with white towel type of thing cover his face.
My memory is probably not very good,
because it's just a glimpse of that.
and wear something probably why they should jeans or some kind of darker pants pants or shorts i don't know it's probably i can't tell because very very quickly that happened he walked kind of looking down he walked over to tv camera and next next thing i know a tv camera is covered
Nanyo had ordered this camera 14 days prior,
and there was a 14-day trial period.
And during that time frame,
he was allowed to capture any images into a cloud that happened,
that was captured on the camera.
So on that day,
when he gets back,
on the 7th,
the 14th day grace period had expired.
So he's not seeing a tape delay.
He's not seeing anything like that.
He's looking live.
The person I know,
you said a male or whatever,
Could you tell if it was a male or a female?
I think it's a male.
Okay.
Rather skinny.
How old did this male look?
20-ish.
Okay.
Looks like,
doesn't look like very old to me.
Okay.
I can't see the face,
so I can't tell,
but from the body language of that,
he's not shrugging,
no,
moving body is rather smooth.
Can you tell what male,
black male,
or?
Looks like white to me.
Okay.
The father then proceeds to call the son and ask the son,
hey,
are you playing around with the camera?
The son says,
no,
I'm not playing around with the camera.
He says,
well,
I saw someone in the home.
Can you go home and check on your mom?
I walk into my garage,
take off my shoes.
I look at my room,
and I have,
there's a drawer in my room with a bunch of knives.
I collect a bunch of knives and stuff.
That was open.
I'm like,
that's weird.
And then
I get to the living room,
and I look left,
and I see that there's,
the camera's been just literally ripped out.
It's not even there anymore.
And then
I hear the water running.
I walk into my parents room and I see her.
She's in the tub.
Water's flowing.
Her face is in the water.
My first thought is I thought she committed suicide because I see there's a lot of blood.
And I just,
I remember
I dragged her out and
I saw her going freaking out.
And I tried giving her,
I tried.
Pushing her,
sorry,
I'm just listening for her breath and just like putting breath into her lungs,
but it just tastes like blood.
Law enforcement gets there and they does their canvas of the neighborhood and they find the lady across the street,
Betty,
who states that sometime around 12.03,
12.05,
she says that she just sees a door close.
It appears that there is a crime scene that occurred in the foyer next to the front door.
Because law enforcement from the crime scene photos,
you can see blood droplets out there,
okay?
So that clearly means that somebody would have had to stab her,
and she'd been stabbed approximately 13 times.
Then picked her up and put her in the tub and filled it up with water.
The first impression of the police when they arrived in the house and they saw the body,
they said this had to be a murder of...
Passion,
like someone who,
whoever did this,
knew this woman.
This was a rage-style murder.
If you're seeing 20,
30 attacks,
particularly if those are occurring to the torso area or the neck or other sensitive areas,
that indicates the person kept stabbing beyond what was absolutely necessary for that crime to have been committed.
And that can indicate,
again,
that emotional closeness.
There's some sort of,
you know,
emotional investment.
The person's angry at the victim.
And
I wish I could tell you,
you know,
every single specific thing,
but there's just some things we have to keep close to the chest.
But,
I mean,
it's just the whole house,
the way it's laid out,
it doesn't seem like,
I mean,
we were at robbery for many years.
It doesn't seem like a home invasion robbery.
The police are saying that the point of entry where the perpetrator may have come through,
no one possibly could have came through that way.
If they did break in in that door,
the first thing to perk what it did was it's opened the back.
He would have unlocked the sliding door so that he had a way to get out.
The detectives confirmed that all the doors in the house were locked.
If you're a burglar and you're going into the house,
at what point after you've killed this lady do you then go back out and then relock the house?
Because there would be a key missing.
And then the whole thing about this case is there's nothing missing in the house.
Nothing's been stolen.
Nothing.
Nothing taken.
There was a iPad,
there was a
MacBook, there was a laptop,
there was iPhones.
Nothing was taken.
Nothing.
So either the person who came there just came to kill that woman,
or they came there and they tried to commit a burglary,
but they left everything that they got behind
And just did this.
It just,
that's not an MO of somebody who burglarizes homes.
So what ended up happening was police questioned the son,
and they questioned the father.
And when they questioned both of them,
each of them,
they had a preconceived notion that one or both of them was responsible for the death.
Of Jill Halliburton Sue.
Let me ask you this.
There seems to be a lot of guilt there.
When he talks about his mom,
he says that she was like ashamed of him.
Why does he say that?
Well,
because he didn't make through his grade,
even,
you know,
make through the two years in Stetson.
He basically dropped out.
And my wife,
having a professor like me as a husband,
probably expect a lot from him.
And he probably always feel pressure that he have to.
You know,
perform.
He didn't.
He couldn't.
Can I speak to you one more thing?
A kind of a little detail here?
Sure.
So,
when we are gone to
Malaysia, my wife told me that she so happened to be seen online on the camera in our dining room,
behind the camera,
that
My son obviously sneaked out from the front,
the side door,
from there,
come back from the other door,
from my bedroom,
or she had a little pastoral wound there.
And then she covered her face.
He covered his face,
okay?
My son covered his face.
And then next thing you know,
he put a towel or something on top of the camera.
That was why you guys were in the hospital.
That's where we are in.
So I know.
that is the reason why initially i suspect this person i saw in in the mask maybe him because he tried to pull the plank on me why would he say that have you ever done that i've thrown like over the camera have you ever put something around your face messing around you know your mom saw it and said oh you're silly or whatever yeah sure about that yeah
put something on my face cover up my face you sure about that yeah that you both your parents were like
I thought it was funny at the time,
but it wasn't.
And they told you don't do that again.
What,
put something over the...
Over your face.
Over my face?
No.
They never...
You never wore anything over your face and did that?
Mask,
or anything like that?
And like scare the camera or something like that?
No.
Yeah,
like to mess around with them while they were away.
No.
Well,
when we were in Malaysia,
he did that.
So my wife was...
Kind of telling him that,
did you do this in front of the camera and come back and cover your face and flop this one here?
And he said,
yeah.
So three of us just laughed because we were so busted on that one.
We were just laughing on that one.
If we were able to do this,
no way the security camera would have done this.
Because both of them being unplugged,
they know this camera.
Well,
let me ask you,
who knows where the security camera is?
My son.
Boom.
Who knows where the security cameras?
My son.
And so when they questioned him for hours and hours and hours,
they made it clear that they believed
Justin Su was a suspect.
They thought,
mom is dead,
dad is gone,
son finds the body,
he's your killer.
The fuck is green?
Dude,
I'm...
I can't...
Shut the fuck up.
Man,
I've been in this room way too long,
man.
Yeah.
Hey,
listen.
A lot of the stuff that we talked about earlier,
the stuff you told us,
doesn't make sense.
What do you mean?
Are you saying that I did it?
Yeah.
Holy crap!
Oh my...
No,
I didn't...
I would never...
I would never do that,
dude.
That's bullshit.
Oh my god!
Oh my god what?
What's so hard to believe?
I did that and I would break into my own?
Nobody broke into my fucking house.
Stop playing this fucking game.
Oh my god,
are you serious?
You know how long we've been doing this fucking job?
A long time.
I know.
That's horrible that you guys would even think that I would fucking do it.
I'm sorry,
but I'm...
You're sorry.
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna go fucking...
You're not gonna go nowhere.
Dude!
I didn't do it!
Your dad tells you there's somebody inside your house that he sees on a camera?
Yeah.
And your first thought is to go home?
Yes!
And you stop your...
Shut up for a minute.
Your first thought is to take off your shoes and go in your bedroom first?
Yeah!
What?
What's wrong with that?
I was gonna check it out.
I had a knife in my hand.
What knife did you have in your hand?
What?
I had a pocket knife.
Which one?
The one from my car.
What does it look like?
It was just in my pocket,
dude.
I just...
Where is it now?
It's in my car still.
I put it back in my car.
What does it look like?
It's black.
So you put that back in your car before the cops got there?
No.
You said you had a knife in your car.
Fuck,
you guys are putting shit in my head now.
You're saying it,
man.
When did you have an opportunity to go to your car?
When I was in my car when I dropped it.
What?
When did you have an opportunity to go to your car?
When I got out of the car?
When did you ask me again?
You're a smart guy.
I'm not trying to insult you.
That whole thing with the knife,
I made up.
Because when you told me,
like,
why would you go in the house,
because I was defending myself.
You made it up?
Yeah.
That's the problem.
Sorry.
Don't do that again.
I just told you,
you're not making sense and your stories are all over the place.
And you're just gonna sit here now and tell me you made that up about going back in your car?
Yeah.
That's the only thing I lied about.
Sorry.
No,
you said you were in BC,
right?
Yeah.
In the library.
Why?
Oh,
I'm just making sure.
So you don't tell me tomorrow,
or later on today,
oh yeah.
I forgot to say,
I wasn't really at the library.
Check the,
check the,
check the garage,
man.
I was,
I was like- You don't need to check the fucking garage.
I don't need to check.
Why not?
Because you said you're in the library.
So?
What's wrong with that?
What if you're not in the library?
Then where were you?
In my car.
What were you doing in your car?
Sleeping.
So I'm gonna ask you the same question again.
So you don't fuck this up.
Be honest with me.
Did you stay in your car sleeping or did you go to the library?
I say that,
okay,
I'm sorry,
I said that too.
You fucking lied about that too.
Because
I don't want to seem like an asshole.
That's two lies.
I'll just point out two.
I mean,
my thing is,
why would you even have to lie?
If you didn't do anything,
if the only thing you did was come home and you found your mom deceased,
why would you lie about anything?
Was she still repeatedly?
Many times?
Viciously?
Yeah.
She was shooting multiple times.
Indicating this more like emotional charge type of rage killer type of thing?
You think?
I don't think so.
Why,
why he tired of that?
Why he tied her up?
It's his mom.
He didn't have to tie her up.
You grabbed your mom,
you pulled her out of the tub,
right?
So you would have had blood on your hands there.
Right?
Because you didn't put any gloves on when you pulled your mom out of the tub.
You didn't have time to.
While you walked through the house,
you would have touched the sliding door,
which means you would have blood on the sliding door handle of your mom.
Yes.
And you would have blood on the lock on the front door of your mom.
Do you agree with me?
Yes,
I agree with you.
That should be there.
Right.
And if there isn't,
what does that mean?
That none of those things happen,
I guess?
I don't know.
Yeah.
And,
you know,
I don't...
That's the reason why I really want to talk to somebody.
I need to know their representation.
Okay.
I'm trying to be very cooperative.
And you have been.
No,
I'm trying to tell everything I know.
And you have been.
I wouldn't say that you haven't.
But since my son is still my son...
I would accept the truth that he did it,
but before that,
we need to make sure that everything is done fairly.
Okay,
everything,
first of all,
is being done fairly.
Okay,
we're not trying to trick anybody or anything like that.
and you just said that if he did it,
you would accept it,
is that what you said?
If in truth,
if the total truth comes out that he did it,
I totally accept that.
If I found out I was wrong,
I'd seriously consider a career change.
Oh my god.
No,
I...
Someone's trying to frame me,
man.
If you're saying someone's trying to frame you,
the only one that's capable of framing you is your dad.
Would your dad frame you?
You can't lie to the police in Broward County on a murder charge.
You can't lie.
Ask some of the people that are down there at the main jail,
can you lie about a homicide and get out the same night?
No.
Anytime you lie about anything in a homicide,
your ass gonna sit.
With them releasing the dad,
I understand that.
And I get that because,
like I said,
all his alibis and everything was trunk tight.
But.
With them releasing
Justin, based on the fact that he lied to them multiple times and he had been released,
I don't know if they had enough to charge him,
but he at least should have spent the night in jail.
If we arrested people on suspicion alone,
there'd be a lot of people arrested and a lot of people wrongfully.
arrested because obviously you suspect a lot of different people but the police have to engage in an investigation until they have material evidence that tends to provide probable cause that someone committed a crime you can't arrest somebody and you can't arrest somebody because they told you that they were at work and then admitted they were sleeping justin
was a kid who was under kind of strange circumstances from his parents he went to college for two years
Because he flunked out,
his parents made him come home.
He'd only been home for a couple of months at the time.
So clearly he's kind of like on probation with his parents.
And I can only imagine,
you know,
the dichotomy of that with a dad whose whole life is academics.
Dr.
Su is obviously a very decorated professor,
and he's very well regarded in his profession.
And,
you know,
the fact that Justin struggled a little bit at school,
I mean,
I can understand the dynamic of the relationship.
It definitely seemed,
I think,
You know,
from both the father and son,
that there was tension in that relationship.
You can see that on one hand,
his father acquiesced fairly quickly to the idea that he might have been the perpetrator.
And,
you know,
when Justin lied,
it was possible that this may have been motivated by fear of his father.
But it would have to be really,
really significant,
I think,
for him to think that lying to investigators was the better choice than simply accepting whatever disagreement with his father might have resulted.
Justin had a lot of knives because he was very into fishing,
which is a common thing in Florida.
A lot of people are into fishing,
and a lot of them have a lot of knives.
But Justin also had,
according to police,
a bit of a heavy drug usage habit.
And he was using something called DAB,
which is apparently 80%
THC.
Now,
anything above 20%
THC is considered high.
And that's not exactly trivial when you're looking at...
What happened with his mother?
Justin's mother had always been very tight,
very close.
But sometimes it's those relationships that are closest to us that cause the most extreme reactions.
There had been more tension in their relationship since he'd come home.
Had there been an argument?
Had there been an escalation in that tension?
We don't know.
Both Dr.
Su and the son were questioned by police and neither have been considered suspects.
However,
I don't want to say anybody's been ruled out or is a suspect.
I mean,
at this time,
this is a very active investigation.
When you have a lot of money,
there are lots of different potential motives.
Did she just recently hurt?
I know her father died about a year ago.
That could mean she came into a lot of money recently.
Who gains money when you die?
Your heirs.
Does she have a will?
Did she promise in that will to give lots of money to?
one of these foundations that she volunteers for?
You've got to think about that question.
The deceased is an heir to the Halliburton fortune.
So the Halliburton Company made millions,
if not billions,
of dollars off the Afghan and
Iraqi war.
If you'll recall,
George Bush gave that company all kinds of work to supply munitions,
supplies,
and everything,
and there were no bid contracts.
Because it was an emergency.
So this is a high profile case.
It's like,
well,
we got to find somebody.
There's a lot of pressure on the police to solve this crime.
And the suits are saying that someone burglarized their home and they killed their mom.
So the first thing the cops are going to do is they're going to start looking at all the burglaries that happened in probably a two or one mile radius of that actual place.
And they're going to start trying to find suspects.
And I think what they did is they just found the suspect.
What happens seven days later,
they process the scene for DNA.
And lo and behold,
they find the knife that was on the front porch.
They do the DNA.
And lo and behold,
there's a hit on Deontay Rosales.
How do you feel about your son?
Do you want me to say something?
No,
how do you feel about your son?
Oh,
I feel like my whole body goes down because he's my first son.
I don't have nobody else.
He was my oldest son.
He was the one who was going to depend on me.
I only have three people who are going to take care of him.
So when I say that,
I don't believe in him.
I believe in him.
Nah,
hang on.
He said that he just felt weak.
You know,
Deontay is his firstborn and,
you know,
that's all.
He depended on us being the oldest,
so he kinda depended on Deontay a lot.
He said it's very emotional for him.
I think seeing Deontay in the position that he is and being a father knowing that he's helpless right now.
Like he can't do anything to help his son,
that he can't hold his son.
You know what I'm saying?
So
I think he's very emotional about it.
Yeah,
it's okay daddy.
You want to take the next fan and wear his long thong?
Thanks,
I'll just hide it.
He was just here.
I'm cool with that.
So,
what's hard for me is that we have...
It pains me to say it,
but we have a black...
Young man in jail for a crime that the husband said he saw videotaped was a white guy.
He clearly states it.
My job as a prosecutor is to do what is just,
not to prosecute any particular person.
When justice demands that a particular person be prosecuted because all the evidence points to that person,
then that's what we do.
But if the evidence had pointed somewhere else.
We would have followed it.
And that's why
I looked at as much stuff as I could possibly,
you know,
look at to ensure that we were on the right path.
And we were.
I guess their theory is that when he saw her there,
he decided to kill her so he wouldn't get caught,
is what I'm guessing they're going to go forward with.
But it's very different than what we've seen from Deontay Rizzo's past.
He doesn't have violent offenses like this where he's ever hurt someone,
stabbed someone.
He's a burglar.
He is somebody who breaks into homes,
steals,
and leaves.
He does not hurt people.
He does not kill people.
He does not maim people.
There's no way he did that.
No way.
I never had a problem out of Deontay fighting and all that.
No.
He was a good child.
A loving,
caring child.
Always wanted to do something.
to help somebody.
I clean up this.
I help you with that.
You want me to cook?
You don't know how to cook.
I learned.
He was moochy,
asked questions.
He wanted to know everything.
So yeah,
he had plenty of questions.
Yeah,
he got an outburst in personality.
He could be the life of the party,
the center of attention.
I always felt like I was independent.
I didn't want to depend on my mama,
so.
I was little like 11 years old.
We were selling avocados.
We had avocados in the back of the house.
We would sell avocados or mangoes.
And then I learned about selling candy.
I started selling candy.
And then from selling candy,
I went to washing cars.
And from washing cars,
I went to cutting grass.
He wanted to be a singer.
He went from singing to cooking,
from cooking to landscaping.
From landscaping to he took a trade in automotive.
Me and him are about the same age.
He used to come up here when he could have been maybe 13,
14 years old.
And he used to always ask my dad for a job.
But we were always busy staffed,
and we had a lot of workers.
So my dad would tell him,
you know what I mean,
sweep up,
help clean up,
help the guys get the shop open up.
He started doing that.
He would end up coming here every morning just to open up,
make a little extra money.
And he just wanted to work.
He just wanted opportunity.
my dad
I ended up liking him as a kid because he worked hard.
We spoke all the time as far as,
you know,
what are you going to do with your life?
You have to,
you know,
work hard,
go to school,
things like that.
So,
you know,
we kept that kind of conversation with him because,
to me,
the kid seemed like he was college material.
You know,
I used to tell him back in the days,
you know,
you're such a smart kid,
you might be the next president.
If you go down where the Cheesecake Factory is,
you keep going like as if you're going towards the beach,
they have a lot of big mansions,
a lot of big houses and stuff.
That's why I used to go at S.L.
Kenney when I was little.
Because,
you know,
I've always been infatuated with the luxury of life and having a big house,
nice car,
and stuff like that.
So I used to go over there.
Even when I wasn't at S.L.
Kenney when I was there,
I'd go over there as a motivation and determination to become better and to get richer and find the happy families,
wanting that happy family because it was just crazy.
You'd just see a bunch of kids around.
They're enjoying life.
They're skateboarding.
They're with their family,
and everybody's smiling and happy.
But when you come back to your reality and your home or whatever,
everybody's depressed or stressing about the bills or kids'
hunger and stuff.
It was depression.
So I always used to try to escape my reality and go to my fantasy.
So I used to go to my fantasy.
And I just walk on the beach and just see different things.
Tends to be in South Florida,
you're either...
Comfortable or really have it or you're scraping,
you're just getting by.
There's not a lot of this mush ball middle where you're kind of comfortable,
but you're not really scraping.
You're not worried.
Moochie used to be in a lot,
man.
He was coming up.
He was just a little boy.
Coming up right here.
It's one of the best neighborhoods.
You want to get out and roll a little bit.
Yeah,
go to the side a little bit.
Hi.
Hey.
You're right here.
Good.
All right,
this one little kid,
I mean,
the kids right here they look for the one little minute of fame before she never do.
Hey,
look what we got in the hood.
All our cars beat up,
don't work.
We gotta push them,
we gotta walk,
we gotta catch the bus.
Hey,
you try to get money the best way you can,
but it's a struggle to survive around here,
man.
It's not like everybody got the same opportunity.
Some make it,
some don't.
We still living with
ACs in the window right here.
On Third Ave,
you had the part that we stayed at.
It wasn't all that bad,
but then you had the other side on Third Ave and 13th that was-
So my mom always used to tell us we couldn't go to that side or whatever because it's too bad.
It's too much drug selling,
people dying,
prostitutes,
a lot of stuff.
And I was with my homeboy.
My homeboy didn't want to go to the store that my mom usually have us go to.
The day he convinced me to go down the street to the other store,
that's the day when life had this change for me.
Because I went down the street,
I've seen all these girls outside,
beautiful women,
booty everywhere.
I've seen all kind of like
The allure of the fast life,
I've seen big cars with big rims,
people with a lot of money and all that other stuff.
If you grow up and everybody's going to school and everybody's eating lunch,
everybody,
you know,
has the same opportunities,
yeah,
you learn that.
But if you come up and you see everybody breaking their houses and everybody is,
you know,
robbing and stealing and doing everything to get ahead for the newest clothes and the newest outfit,
you see that as a kid and that's your surroundings,
that's what you grow up doing.
It's part of the process.
When you don't have nothing better else to do,
and you're looking at your situation,
kind of make you feel like you need to do something,
you know?
And unfortunately,
when you think about doing something,
the quickest way to do something is to do something wrong.
Because wrong is right there every day in front of you,
you know?
And wrong can make you money in this country.
He got arrested for B&E,
him and some other boys.
They sent him off to
Dozier School for boys That was a level
6A.
You could be in there from six months to eight months.
And he was doing good when he got out of the program,
to be honest with you.
It's just he got out here and continued hanging with the wrong people.
I see a little bit of myself in him when I talk to him when I was younger,
and how that anger and that feel like being cheated because you're not getting a proper childhood that a normal child gets.
So that could be one of two ways you can get.
Angry?
Well,
you could do something about it.
I think Deontay was in the middle of that.
You know,
he would buy turkeys and stuff like that and give it back to single mothers and things like that.
So he was kind of like a neighborhood hero,
you know,
especially when you're coming from a community that's like kind of downtrodden and,
poor.
When I went to set up an account,
I bumped into some lady.
She said that he helped pay her light bill was $407 and her own grandkids wouldn't even help her pay her light bill.
And she said,
your son paid it for me.
I've been in here since she was born.
Like,
she brought her to visitation.
And just seeing her on the screen,
she had her tongue all out.
She had her tongue out.
But just looking at her,
and she's just spitting images of me.
Like,
she looks just like me.
And just seeing her just staring or whatever.
Because I remember the first time when I found out she had the baby.
And then I tried to get in touch with her.
And then when I heard her,
like,
I heard her cry,
I broke down crying.
That's the first time,
I believe that was my second time that I cried,
ever been in jail,
and that was the last time I cried.
But she just brought me joy.
You know the feeling that you get when you bring your first child and then you bring your first child home.
But me and her,
like,
we never had the connection of,
you know,
I got to see her,
hold her,
kiss her,
or spend time with her or whatever.
It's kind of hard being in here,
but I'll have my time soon.
The state had the chance to file it as a regular murder case where he would have been facing just a life sentence.
Or they could charge it as a death penalty case,
which they decided to do.
And so for Deontay,
it looks like they're saying that the way that the woman died was so heinous,
atrocious,
and cruel that it merits the death penalty from their point of view.
The most significant reason for the committee to decide that this was a case in which seeking the death penalty is appropriate was the fact that Mrs.
Sue was in her own home,
that she was tied up.
That she was alive for some period of time after being tied up,
that she was placed in a bathtub,
and that then she was brutally stabbed so many times.
And you've got to think about the terror.
And if we don't do our job the best that we can,
he's going to die.
He's going to be killed by the state of Florida.
That weighs very heavy on us.
It's just,
you know,
to be facing something that he's facing,
which is death,
with the lack of evidence that there is.
It's just almost impossible to believe that my guy was even arrested in the first place for a murder,
but this is Broward County,
so.
Within the last hour or so,
the Broward County Sheriff's Crime Lab announced that it's no longer going to do some DNA analysis,
a cornerstone of its operation,
and the lab faces losing its accreditation.
NBC6 investigator Tony Pipitone has been following the science here and joins us live at the newsroom with more on this.
Tony.
Yeah,
the experts who give the lab its accreditation found errors in how it analyzed DNA.
Mistakes that lawyers say could implicate innocent people.
That's why the lab just now has agreed to stop doing some DNA tests and will have to pay another lab to do them.
All this while it fights to keep its accreditation.
Defense attorney Monique Brochu knew last year something was not right with DNA evidence coming from Broward's crime lab.
It was the only physical evidence helping place her client,
Javon Gibson,
at the scene of an April 2010 murder.
So Brochu brought in DNA expert Tiffany Roy,
who found the Broward Sheriff's crime lab was misinterpreting DNA evidence,
an accusation confirmed by a board that determines how crime labs should operate.
The very first case that I ever consulted on for a defense attorney was a Broward County case,
and it was done completely wrong.
The case had a profile that I would consider to be unreliable.
It was too limited information,
too unreliable information,
but Broward County went ahead and made an association with it,
matched it to a defendant,
and I didn't know how they could do that with this limited data.
You're supposed to look at the sample independently of anything else.
You're supposed to make a determination if that sample that you have,
that partial sample,
is enough to go forward with a match,
okay?
But you're supposed to look at it independently of anything else.
What was happening in the BSO crime lab is they were taking the mixed samples,
they were extrapolating them out,
realizing,
okay,
we have three partial samples of three people.
Now,
when they realized they couldn't go forward,
they were supposed to stop.
But instead of stopping at that point,
what they were doing was taking the known samples,
the people that they wanted it to be,
okay?
And they were saying,
oh,
look,
here's Monique's client.
And Monique's client and this one,
we kind of match it and it kind of is matchy-matchy and okay,
we'll do that one.
And this one,
okay,
this is another guy and it's kind of good and it kind of matches here and there.
Okay,
we'll do that one.
So it was like they were playing a game.
Instead of doing what they were supposed to do independently,
they were just trying to match it up with the known samples.
The lab's accrediting agency board agreed the lab is making mistakes,
using portions of DNA so minuscule they should have been disregarded,
and being biased,
considering the DNA of a suspect before deciding what portions of DNA recovered from evidence would be used to connect him to the crime.
We all work for someone.
Somebody pays our bills.
We're influenced by that,
no question.
Some of the crime labs are paid by the state police.
Some of them wear badges in the lab.
Do they have a special relationship with the police,
with law enforcement?
Of course they do.
Most people who work in labs get all the information about their lives.
case they may have emails sometimes from prosecutors and the emails are like you know we really got to get this guy does that have an effect on the science yes cognitive bias is real it's well established and a great example
of this is the study by the National Institute of Standards and Technology 2013 they gave the same mixture data to 109 crime labs and they asked is suspect a
be C?
Are they included in this ski mask from a bank robbery?
But they created the data so that for suspect C,
it was really hard to tell whether C was included or not.
76 of 109 North American crime labs said suspect C is included.
Suspect C was not included by the National Institute of Standard Technology.
It was a distractor.
It was a tough problem to see when labs would say
it's inconclusive.
And instead,
76 labs said this person is included.
That doesn't mean we don't trust the DNA.
I think the DNA is very helpful if it helps show someone didn't commit a crime.
But to convict,
we require a jury to find beyond a reasonable doubt.
And that's a super high standard.
I would hope that if all of the other evidence conflicts with the DNA,
you might not want to trust the DNA.
The way that DNA has been portrayed in film,
on TV,
in movies,
is that if you got someone's DNA,
you're able to identify them.
It's an open and shut case.
The reality is,
it's far more complicated than just open and shut.
I'm old enough to be embarrassed about some of the things we used to believe about DNA.
We used to testify to a high degree of scientific certainty without having...
calculated the certainty because I was taught,
as the FBI taught people,
to testify that way,
to say,
I am sure of my results to a high degree of scientific certainty.
And then somebody said,
you know,
that's actually a mathematical calculation.
Did you do that?
Because if we say Greg Hampikian could have contributed the DNA,
we want to know,
well,
who else could have contributed?
How many other people?
DNA evidence cannot say that
You are in fact a match.
It can say that you are likely a match within the reasonable likelihood of multiples and multiples of the tens of thousands.
There's no exact
100% match,
but the media has already convinced a lot of folks that DNA,
if you have it,
then you've proved it.
But it's a lot more complex.
This calculation was
Part of my complaint that I filed against Broward initially,
because they weren't using this right,
and their accrediting body agreed with my assessment,
basically,
and found that there were some problems with the way they were interpreting these low-level mixed profiles and assigning weights to them for statistical purposes.
This is a case that would be affected by that.
It's very likely that individuals have gone through this system on faulty evidence.
and ultimately have been convicted based on poor evidence.
So we're optimistic that this might benefit
Mr. Reziles'
case because as I think I indicated to you earlier,
it appears that the only link at this point in time to Mr.
Reziles to that crime scene is some DNA that was on two items that were found at the crime scene.
We're taking depositions now of the people that collected the DNA sample first.
Before we get to the people that analyzed it so that we get an idea of how it was collected,
what was done with it before it got to the lab,
those kind of things.
This is a death penalty state.
You know,
we execute people here.
And it absolutely needs to be done right.
And nowhere is it more important than in states that do that.
Every day,
I promise you,
every day I'm always planning and strategizing of how I can make the best of every situation and how to alter and change everything in life to make it better or whatever.
I'm driven to do it or whatever,
but it's hard doing it when you're confined to a freaking cell 23 hours a day and these people treat you like shit.
It's hard.
Sam,
if you know,
like I told you,
they act,
this place was like a,
acted as a concentration camp for me.
The stuff that they do to...
Mentally torture you emotionally and all that spiritually.
They did this in every way they possibly could,
but I still remain unbroken.
Only thing they haven't done yet is kill me.
I'm tired Sam,
I'm tired.
Well,
he wouldn't be the first person,
the first person charged with a serious crime to feel that the system moves too slow.
But as I explained to my client,
you want to move it fast?
Go in and plead guilty.
Otherwise,
let your attorneys have sufficient time to prepare these cases.
There's a lot of depositions to be taken.
There's various pretrial motions to be filed.
And remember,
you get one trial,
and then it's just a matter of logistics.
I've got,
at this point in time,
I've got a half dozen murder cases.
So
I've got to work on
all those at the same time.
I'm in trial on other murder cases that predate
Mr. Rezile's case,
so that takes me away from prep time here.
There's nothing to be served in a case of this magnitude by rushing to trial.
When life brings you to that point of depression or when you're sad and you're depressed or anything,
you just look at it.
You have the power to change it.
In your mind,
you have the strength.
to change anything that's wrong in life and that you don't like or that has you feeling depressed or anything you have the power to change it and then it's the same way if somebody tries to come and bring harm to you or harm to your family you have to defend yourself you have to fight you have to stand firm you can't let nobody back you down because if you allow somebody to back you down then you lose but when you stand firm and you fight that's when people back off
BOOM!
What just happened?
21-year-old Deontay Reziles had been in jail for almost 22 months.
He went to the courthouse this morning for a hearing on whether he could someday face the death penalty.
It's now been more than 13 hours since the murder suspect managed to make a mad dash from that hearing.
NBC6 continues to cover all angles of this manhunt.
SWAT teams went to work searching for Reziles,
but it was too late.
The Broward Sheriff's Office says that this is a violent criminal.
He is.
armed and dangerous.
If you see him,
call police immediately.
No,
Rezaiel,
as you know,
is
21 years old.
He's approximately 5 feet 10.
He's 170 pounds.
He has tattoos on both arms.
And he is armed and dangerous.
Let me repeat that.
He is armed and dangerous.
21-year-old Deyante Rezaiel had been in jail for almost 22 months.
He went to the courthouse this morning for a hearing on whether he could someday face the death penalty.
But before that could happen,
Rezaiel somehow got loose from his handcuffs
and bolted from the fourth floor of the courthouse.
He made another surprising move,
not only ditching his jumpsuit,
but removing his handcuffs.
One of the court deputies actually was able to grab his pants,
but he was able to break that grab and continue out the door.
Police would spend hours sweeping every inch of the courthouse before finally realizing the accused murderer had made it out into the streets of Fort Lauderdale.
Resiles spreading panic in the courthouse this morning after bolting during a peak hour.
His escape putting the areas near the courthouse on alert.
Swarms of officers with guns blocked off roads and combed through possible hideaways.
This was a tremendous embarrassment for them.
I mean,
you lost an inmate?
You didn't just lose an inmate in transition.
You lost him.
He was in the courtroom.
If you embarrass the sheriff's office,
if you embarrass any entity of law...
I mean,
there's going to be hell to pay.
I must be some kind of creature up there having been.
Having a hard time in this crazy town.
Having a hard time.
There's no love to be found.
I don't know what he,
you know,
I have no idea.
Like I said,
I walked in.
I wasn't even actually at the courtroom.
I just saw all this commotion as I walked up.
And then people said,
your client just escaped.
And at first I thought it was a joke.
I said,
your client just ran away.
Yeah,
okay,
sure.
Then I found out it was for real.
I was walking downstairs when I heard a commotion and I went outside and a couple minutes later found out that someone had escaped from the courtroom.
And in my mind I thought,
well,
they'll just catch him and put him back in the jail.
No big deal.
We've all had clients that have freaked out in court,
but they usually are really quick to take them down.
When I found out he left,
I thought that was unbelievable.
He will always be known as the young man that escaped the Robert Carter jailhouse for the rest of his life.
He made history.
So you have several people coming from the jail.
They're all shackled together.
And they're in the...
what would normally be the jury box,
all these jail inmates.
And suddenly,
he bounds up,
over,
out.
He hits the door.
Actually,
there's a little bit of resistance in the door.
I think somebody was on the other side.
And then kind of pushes again on the door,
and he's out the door.
Everybody's...
kind of like,
what just happened?
Like,
the judge went,
so they're like,
order in the court!
Like,
which,
you know,
you only really see in the movies.
That never really happens in real life.
But,
you know,
nobody thinks he's really going to get too far,
because the courthouse is full of deputies.
But somehow he had it planned out to go down to a certain stairwell where there was actually an exit behind the courthouse that he could leave,
which was pretty strange.
They're evacuating the building here.
I'm sorry,
Jim.
They're evacuating our building.
We have to leave.
Before anybody can process what they've just witnessed,
Deontay Rosillas has escaped.
And nobody knows what to do.
Has anyone reviewed the videotape to determine what ingress and egress points he chose?
Bravo 3,
do you remember if he was cuffed at the time?
I just found a jumpsuit on the ground,
so I'm not sure what he's wearing.
Every tactical unit I have available to me and all our assets and resources,
our canine,
our helicopters,
our Marine Patrol.
Looking for Mr.
Reziles.
All of the law enforcement agencies across the U.S.
have been notified about this guy.
Take a look at him.
That is his photo.
I just laughed.
I was just amazed.
I'm just,
I'm telling God,
you got a sense of humor.
You funny,
you know?
I'm just in...
Join the moment.
The reward money for information leading to Rosales has jumped significantly.
And possibly most telling is the sheriff saying they believe he had accomplices.
It was a plan that was concocted by teenagers,
of all the things.
His girlfriend at the time was only 19.
She was driving a BMW,
and she picked him up downstairs.
So it was well planned.
Everybody was impressed.
About this kid,
how a young black man from the hood can pull off an escape.
It was very coordinated.
It was very organized.
Who would have thought?
Not only was it daring,
I mean,
it was downright.
He just,
he was perfectionist.
He spent several weeks talking over the phone,
going over everything,
making sure all the T's was crossed and all the I's was dotted.
The big question that everybody had,
of course,
is where did he get the key?
They thought possibly it was brought in by maybe an attorney.
Maybe a friend visiting.
Where he got the key wasn't clear.
What we do know is that Deontay got one of his fellow inmates to loosen his shackles beforehand so he could slip out of them once he got into the courtroom.
We also know that he asked one of his friends to do a dry run 10 days before his escape,
so he knew exactly which way to go after he fled the courtroom.
Remember the number that I put on the paper,
the 480,
and all the other stuff?
Yeah,
that's where I'm at right now.
All right,
so you tell me which one you feel like best.
Macho side.
My old girl side,
the best one?
Yeah.
Alright,
alright,
alright.
So,
go and just see if they shoot nice over there.
Alright.
It looks like they were shooting nice over there.
But you got to be quick on your feet after you leave your old girl house.
That's the only thing it is,
but I'm out here right now looking at this shit.
You got to be quick on your feet after you come out your old girl house,
bruh.
Yeah.
That's it,
bruh.
I'm going to be right there.
Now,
he also planned another detail.
Might not seem like nothing to me and you,
but it was perfect for his escape.
Deontay made slits in his prison jumpsuit so he could easily slip out of it.
Just in case any of the deputies grabbed him as he was fleeing the courtroom.
The inmate made a run for the door.
The bailiff was directly right behind him,
tried to grab his jumpsuit,
but I think he got out of his jumpsuit and just kept running.
So Deonte's plan of escape was to exit the courthouse on the side building,
travel down this sidewalk to this street right here.
His waiting vehicle was parked right here where they actually were able to escape down the driveway and get away.
So the first place Deonte goes after he flees the jail is his uncle's house to get money because if you're out on the run you need cash.
Second,
they drove Deontay to this parking lot in this apartment complex off of Oakland Park Boulevard.
This is where they dropped him off.
They
dropped him off about right over here somewhere.
She picked him up wearing some like hooter shorts just casually just picked him up like nothing had even happened
Meanwhile, they still looking for Deontay in the courthouse
All units be advised we now have him on camera.
He left the building at 934 through stairwell one
Okay, have somebody in the control room
Print me out some color photos of him so I can distribute them throughout the perimeter points to Fort Lauderdale
The escape was like all over the news,
and it was very hugely published because,
of course,
he was on the run.
There was a manhunt for him.
It's interesting.
I don't recall it being as if,
oh,
my goodness,
there's a murderer on the loose,
you know,
there's some,
like a,
I mean,
like a serial killer or something.
It was just,
it was more like,
what?
Huh?
Okay,
let's see what's next.
Are they going to catch him?
You know,
it almost,
I think people almost treat it a little bit like a movie.
Or a mini series,
okay,
what's next?
The sheriff's office needed to gather intelligence and fast.
They had two options.
Interview his fellow inmates and listen to his jailhouse calls.
We switched phones.
He wanted to stay out the window.
Why was that?
Was that unusual?
He just said it's his last day,
he just wanted to get a good view.
That's all he said.
Okay,
so he switched phones with you because it was his last day?
It was his last day and I put in my radio.
That was it.
Investigators found out that Deontay was using somebody else that was locked up with him's PIN number,
so the cause couldn't be traced back to him.
And so what he would do was,
is he would call that inmate's girlfriend,
and she would hook him up with all his accomplices,
and that's how they mastered it out.
Did you ever hear anybody either on the three ways or anybody?
No one else.
I just.
Hold on.
I'm going to have to ask you the question first.
Oh.
Name of Winston?
I heard that name last night,
but I didn't know who it was.
I just remembered him saying something about,
don't say,
you know,
I'm not going to say too much on the phone.
What was that?
Moochie?
Moochie,
yeah.
He was like,
I'm not going to say too much on the phone.
You already know what,
you know,
what you got to do.
Something like that.
And who was he talking to?
He was talking to his girlfriend,
Quay.
Quay?
Yeah.
So after the police went through all the text messages and all the jail calls,
they figure out that LaQuay and Winston picked him up from the courthouse.
They arrested him the very next morning.
All right,
like I said,
I know you understand how serious the situation is.
And we've had
200 cops looking for him all day.
It's been almost 24 hours.
We still have 15 detectives.
You saw at your house,
U.S.
Marshals were there.
We want to take care of this.
No.
We know.
And I can prove that you know a lot more than you're leading on.
So after investigators threatened them with long jail sentences,
they went ahead and caved.
They gave them everything and told them everything they knew about the escape.
I picked up the twins.
Okay.
After I picked up the twins,
we was in traffic until we got to the courthouse.
Who were the twins?
Okay,
so the twins are Mushi's cousins.
What did they do up in the courtroom to help this out?
Cough.
When they coughed,
I knew that he was there.
Oh,
man.
Excuse me,
sir.
I'm being detained.
You're being arrested.
I'm being arrested?
Yeah.
What's the charges?
Accessory to murder and accessory to escape.
Isn't any of this shit worth it?
I'll just be doing dumb shit and other things.
I tell you all the time,
all this bullshit,
don't correct it.
It's gonna affect your future,
bro.
I can't go home?
Nope.
Not even if I cooperated?
Well,
you had that opportunity.
You already decided you didn't want to talk.
You're changing your mind?
Would I let him go home?
Do you know where he is now?
sir.
Probably not then.
How come?
Because that's what we want.
A CBS 4 News safety alert is still in place because the accused killer who escaped from the Broward County Courthouse last Friday is still on the loose.
The Broward Sheriff's Office has arrested four people suspected of helping him get away.
Broward Sheriff's Office,
again,
very embarrassed.
They want people to know we're doing things.
The arrest forms come out and some of the details about how they believed.
These people helped Rosales came out.
Deputies add that Rosales'
girlfriend LaQuay Stern was waiting outside in a silver BMW while their friend Winston Russell had his hand on the steering wheel of the getaway car.
There's an undercurrent among those who know Rosales and know about these cases.
There's an undercurrent of he was being hung up,
rung up on that kind of as an excuse.
Okay,
here's somebody weak in railroad.
That's,
there's an undercurrent of that feeling because...
There's evidence of this.
This is not,
you know,
it's not like that hasn't happened before.
Well,
tonight he's trending on Twitter and Facebook with some users actually encouraging the accused killers run from the law.
This Facebook Live video titled,
They Said Moochie Hyden in This Hotel,
is just the latest in the social media frenzy over Deontay Rosales'
escape from the Broward County Courthouse on Friday.
Rosales,
whose nickname is Moochie,
was not at this Fort Lauderdale motel.
The manager is saying...
Someone called in a tip,
so deputies have to check it out.
Meanwhile,
the hashtag RunMucciRun has gained attention as people jokingly refer to him as El Mucci after the legendary drug lord El Chapo.
If I'm around here,
then don't come.
Run from them,
just go dumb.
Always on the road,
getting to the door.
Nigga gotta make a little something.
I can settle down,
bitch,
I'm young.
Don't try to jump,
I got a gun.
If I'm crack or slide,
boy,
you better hide.
Or better yet,
just run.
Say go.
Run,
Mucci.
Run.
Go.
Go,
Mucci.
I made the song like right on the spot,
you know,
as soon as I heard about it,
put it out and it immediately received a lot of feedback,
positive feedback.
People were on Twitter tweeting about it.
I had people already making videos,
you know,
saying run,
Moochie,
run.
That kind of went viral when he escaped the courtroom.
I think that that just speaks to a larger issue that we have here locally when it comes down to
Police lying and covering up crimes and really incriminating black people for crimes that they didn't commit.
I just feel like that's the sense of,
I guess,
loyalty and you're down for the cause,
because they're probably tired of police brutality because around that time,
that's when people were getting shot by the police.
Let's say you knew where he was right now.
Honestly,
did you?
That place?
Yeah,
that's where I was.
Probably not.
I appreciate that.
Appreciate that.
That's keeping it real right there.
A man has been committed of a brutal murder,
and yet his whole community stands behind him and supports him.
They can very well just delete him and just say,
you know what,
but they support him.
So far,
so good,
you know?
They didn't catch him yet,
so I don't know.
I don't really know exactly what he's going through and why he's on the run,
but.
You know,
I hope everything works out for the best,
you know.
And tonight we are learning that the reward has now doubled from $10,000 after a donation.
It is now at $20,000.
If you have any information,
call Broward Crime Stoppers at
954-493-TIPS. The first tips received by the sheriff's office were from Deontay's own supporters,
designed to throw off the investigators.
But as time went on,
the sheriff's office increased the reward money.
And put more pressure on the potential informants to talk.
And the tips got more specific.
I was supposed to meet him at a hotel.
Uh-huh.
And what were you going to do?
Why were you going to contact him at the motel?
Because Moochie says a lot of shit to a lot of people and they never follow through.
So go ahead and tell me why.
Why is he going to meet you at the motel?
And why,
after he's on the run,
is he going to hook back up with you?
He was supposed to give some money.
Okay.
One of his cousins asked me,
can I take her to go drop him off a couple items?
And she just said,
can I please take her?
So I took her,
we dropped him off a wig and some contacts over to a residence where he was located at.
And how certain are you that the person who you met with there was Moochie?
A hundred percent.
Did you have any conversation with him?
Yes,
he walked to my car.
How close would you say you came face to face with Moochie?
Close enough to kiss him.
Okay.
Why do you think that was?
Why would he need those clothes?
They was going,
getting ready to leave for Orlando.
Okay.
And do you know the cousin's name?
Yes,
Francine.
Be very,
very careful.
You understand how big your situation is.
You're here in handcuffs,
in shackles,
about to go to jail on a very,
very serious charge.
Please,
sir,
please.
Come on.
On a very,
very serious charge.
What a chance,
sir.
I gave you 16 minutes.
What about the chances?
You took three of those and got a slug on my ass.
Please,
listen to me.
Tell me where Gucci is.
More than a half dozen co-conspirators of friends and family members who have all since been arrested for their roles in the elaborate escape.
So five days after Deontay's escape,
The Broward County Sheriff's Office had seven people in custody,
but they still had no clue as to where Deontay was hiding.
This was tremendously embarrassing for them.
I remember the reward for information was $20,000 right out of the gate or something like that.
You have murders where the initial reward is $3,000.
So the fact that they put
$20,000 out there right off the bat told you they wanted this kid badly and they were very embarrassed by it.
My advice to him would voluntarily surrender right now.
I don't want anything happening to him,
and I don't want anything happening to any innocent third person.
A wanted man is on the run today,
and the reward for help in finding him has been raised.
$50,000 is now being offered for anyone who can help police find Deontay Reza.
Police are really hoping that this extra cash will lead to his recapture.
This is America.
Money talks.
People have a price.
Rosales himself later said it was an uncle who led police to him for the reward.
Do move into position.
You are just sector 7.
Give up perimeter with unit 6.
Every day I was only sleeping for like 30 minutes to an hour at the most.
You know when you're there you're so nervous,
you're nervous like...
Every time something...
that door shut,
door snap,
you're nervous,
you're rushing trying to see what's going on in there.
And even...
it just was a scary day.
Problem was cleared.
Copy that,
I go.
Proceed with caution.
10-4.
This is Reckless.
You need to come.
Opening clear.
We have a visual.
I had so many red dots,
so many .
You would have thought I had chicken pox.
So I thought they was going to kill me.
I stood there,
like,
waiting for it to happen,
but it never happened.
Because I thought I was going to die.
Before I walked out,
I prayed and I said,
if I'm going to die,
don't let it be that long.
Don't allow me to suffer that long.
Just let it be quick.
Because that's all I can say.
I didn't think I was going to make it back here.
I didn't believe none of that.
I just thought they were going to kill me.
He came out of the room.
He surrendered without incident.
He laid on the ground.
He allowed us to handcuff him.
No force was necessary.
Have you shared any words with him?
I just looked at him and he said,
Sheriff's here.
A murder suspect who escaped from the Broward County Courthouse is back behind bars after deputies caught
21-year-old Deontay Reziles hiding out at a Days Inn in West Palm Beach.
Yeah,
when I came back...
For the first time,
I was able to get a good night's sleep because I never sleep past the hour or 30 minutes.
So when they finally caught me and I came in here,
I was able to sleep for hours,
hours,
hours.
I was able to sleep,
and I was all right.
But because I didn't have to worry no more.
I didn't have to worry about the police coming or me being shot or me doing this.
I was all right.
Because they don't have anything,
they was hoping that was going to happen,
that he would be killed out there.
Case over,
case solved,
and the real murder still out for you.
But God had another plan.
Oh,
my goodness.
I thought he was already gone far away.
So I'm like,
oh,
yeah,
they may not ever find him.
I thought he went to another country.
But he only made it on West Palm Beach.
And I'm like,
uh.
I thought he had,
like,
a greater plan.
Like,
he already had everything in place.
To go far away.
I thought he was in Haiti somewhere.
I don't know.
Deontay Rizal's may be the most closely guarded inmate in Broward County,
but he still has a right to pen and paper.
And that's what he used to write this letter to Judge Raag Singhal.
I want to apologize for escaping from your courtroom,
Rizal's writes.
I hope you don't take it personal.
I felt I was at a dead end with nowhere to turn to.
I tried to appeal to everyone to prove to them I was innocent.
But my voice went unheard.
When I escaped,
my whole reason was to gather enough info on my case to prove my innocence,
he writes.
Now he's going to be charged with escape.
An escape in Florida is punishable by a maximum sentence of 15 years.
So the bottom line is he has no defense to the escape charge.
I mean,
it's not like he didn't do it.
He did it.
It's on video,
him running out.
Now he's apprehended,
so he's got to be concerned that any judge is going to give him the maximum sentence for escaping,
which is 15 years.
What was a stronger case for us,
because of our client's desperation,
became a weaker case for us.
With him trying to escape,
any time that you try to flee from police or flee prosecution,
they're able to use that against you at trial as consciousness of guilt,
even though it happened way after the crime.
They can tell the jury,
you know,
innocent people don't run away,
innocent people don't flee,
innocent people don't try to escape prosecution.
They try to show that they didn't do anything wrong.
The value I saw in the escape is the lengths he went.
To organize it.
Someone who is capable of organizing,
even though he knows that he's going to,
you know,
involve people who are potentially going to get in trouble for helping him and doesn't care,
just goes ahead and does it.
That's someone who's capable of doing anything for themselves.
And
I think that that relates to someone who's capable of killing somebody because they're about to get caught.
A murder suspect who escaped from the Broward County Courthouse faced a judge.
in the same courtroom where he broke out of his handcuffs and took off.
This time,
21-year-old Deontay Reziles was guarded by a team of armed deputies.
Reziles'
brother,
family,
and friends packed the courtroom wearing shirts,
innocence until proven guilty.
He mouthed a message to his family in the courtroom that didn't sit well with the many deputies guarding the door.
Reziles'
brother was escorted out of the hearing,
and Reziles'
family left court defending his choice to run.
saying he's been wrongly accused of killing Jill Sue in her Davie home back in 2014.
No,
we're not saying that.
We're saying,
like,
y'all know he escaped from the courthouse,
but he's not the murderer.
I think he's innocent,
and I believe he deserve a fair trial.
They just want a closed case,
so they pent that on him.
I believe he was framed.
You know how many black boys,
you know,
sitting in jail like that?
You don't get support like that.
You know,
like this,
especially like where he come from.
And you don't get an outpour of support like that.
He got his auntie that been,
you know,
Lele been sticking in there from day one.
That got to be gone.
Harry said,
hey,
my brother would never do something like that.
Me and him break into houses before.
And if the house is occupied,
we run to hell out of there.
You know,
we're not going to go attack somebody.
I mean,
which burglar,
you know,
walks in there and attack somebody like that?
Go out.
Leave out.
They want to lock this black.
kid up because they know that that woman's son killed her they know it's the boy yeah even when the first detective was on the scene he was willing to say he'll put his whole career on it if it's not the son exactly so he said i bet it's the son who did it but i mean it just didn't make any sense to me and you just this one black boy you're going into a that's like any white person come over here i mean you sit out we're gonna see you i mean everybody gonna see you don't care who he is you go anywhere around you're gonna see you now there's one black boy going in this whole big community and don't nobody see him,
he go in there and leave.
And don't nobody see.
Uh-oh.
Oh,
they hear us talking about Deontay.
Me and my mom was sitting at the dinner table,
and his mugshot popped up.
She said,
oh,
I remember this kid from 2014,
you know.
This lady got murdered.
It was such a gruesome murder.
And.
I don't,
you know,
he didn't do it.
I don't think he did it.
She followed up the story because there was a lot of other,
you know,
information on the story.
And a lot of it was coming from
Deontay's family.
And they invited her to the court hearing,
which she attended.
And that's the first time she saw him.
And it was a really good connection that I made with his aunt and his brother.
And then one day,
his cousin called and said,
hey.
Moochie says that he wants to see you,
and he wants you to come to the jail.
So we met up,
and then we end up going to see Deontay.
I was watching him the whole time,
like every move that he,
everything that he did,
like the way he held the phone,
everything.
I was watching him,
like analyzing him,
you know,
see if I could kind of read him.
One visit turned into like every other week,
once a week,
and then twice a week.
So
I spent a lot of time talking to him on the phone,
and I visited him.
She didn't waste any time.
The first thing she said,
she's like,
I have something.
I think I have something I need to tell you.
So when she said that,
you are like,
Being a man,
you already know what that leads up to.
It could only be one or two things.
It's something bad or it's something good.
But being that I don't know her or I didn't know her or whatever,
it couldn't have been nothing bad.
So I knew what was coming at the origin there.
And she told me,
I think I like you.
And then from there,
she just became my lady.
And then the loyalty that she gave me,
the love and affection she showered me with,
I lost my sense of proportion.
I just fell for her or whatever.
It was crazy.
She's a wonderful woman.
She's a wonderful...
She's actually,
if I'm gonna be honest,
like,
I don't deserve her because she's too good for me.
And then they would write letters.
She would send him a lot of pretty cards and she'd send him love cards and,
you know,
nice things to emotionally get him,
away from all the difficulty he was struggling with in there because jail is not a...
easy life she did that to make him feel better to help him emotionally like she gave me a purpose like my daughter gives me a purpose of living and breathing and fighting but crystal enhanced the purpose like drove me and motivated me and like in so many ways she kept me grounded or whatever because it's one thing of
having that person in your ear that's repeatedly like you need to get yourself together uh i'm here with you why you keep pushing me away because
In the beginning of our relationship,
it was a power struggle.
Like,
I'm like,
I'm always constantly pushing her away.
Like,
I'm just not prone to trusting people like that because I've been betrayed.
Or I'm not,
like,
she's trying to give me love,
but I'm refusing.
Like,
I'm all right,
I'm all right.
Because it's just like the stuff that I've been through.
But she never gave up.
She always like,
I'm here,
I'm not going anywhere.
I love Deontay.
There's nothing that I wouldn't do for him.
I wouldn't do anything.
There's nothing that I wouldn't do.
And people say,
they'll say like,
oh,
you don't even know him.
You never touched him.
So how can you fall in love with him?
I don't know.
To me,
it's a spiritual thing.
It's more spiritual than anything else.
She never know me.
Like,
we never touched each other hands.
We never kissed each other.
Like,
we never shared a kiss.
But we shared the emotions.
We shared the conversation.
And we shared the connection.
You don't have to necessarily touch a person.
All you have to do is share a sense of affection or.
Words with a person,
like,
love doesn't have a set time when you fall in love or how you fall in love.
Like,
people fall,
a lot of people fall in love in mysterious ways.
Like,
it's not no set standard of how you fall in love and who you fall in love with.
It just sort of happens organically.
This is not normal behavior.
I'm aware of that.
People don't just meet somebody and just will do anything for them.
I'm aware.
And it might be kind of crazy to some people.
Maybe I am crazy.
I don't know.
Only God knows why
I became a part of his life.
Should I do a live on his
Instagram? I mean Facebook.
Say Billboard released Justice for Lucci.
I don't know.
Show you got back up.
I'll go.
That's a good movie.
The billboard posted outside Broward Sheriff's headquarters claims there are two victims,
obviously Jill Halliburton Sue,
found slashed to death in her Davie home in 2014.
But also,
they argue,
the then
19-year-old man who police say left his DNA on the murder weapon and inside the victim's house.
The Broward Sheriff's Office is the one county agency,
the one city agency.
That can say,
you know,
we have the power to stop this.
We have the power to show somebody else committed this crime.
His supporters wanted the sheriff to see it.
Lex,
do you want us on the sidewalk or straight to you?
Straight to him,
pretend he's not there.
Just walk right past him.
Don't stop in front or we'll have to do this again.
OK,
I got you.
I'm tired of walking.
I understand.
That means.
Um,
what got you so interested in this cause?
Tony,
it's been so many people,
so many of our people,
that have just been railroaded through the justice system.
It's just not fair.
And it continues to happen day after day.
It's a lot of court cases,
a lot of people that's in jail right now,
a lot of people of color,
black people that's in jail for the crimes they didn't commit.
But prosecutors will also point to his daring escape from the courthouse as evidence of consciousness of guilt.
If he was innocent,
why escape?
Let's be honest about our public defense system,
it sucks.
I mean,
that's everywhere around the country.
It's horrible.
It's really horrible.
I mean,
you got these public defense lawyers,
they got like probably 20 cases there.
They just can't get everybody.
They just can't do a job effective enough.
And he doesn't have the financial means to hire his own personal attorney.
So when you're going through those factors,
and they're trying to give you the death penalty and everything,
I mean,
he has a fighting soul.
He has the spirit of our ancestors.
He's going to fight.
So.
Let me get up out of here,
let me try to fight,
and let me try to prove my own innocence.
Because I don't believe my defense attorneys is doing the best job they,
I believe that they can do.
Well,
I thank you for coming out here.
I know it was hard for you to get out.
Tony,
I appreciate you letting me,
giving us this opportunity.
I really do appreciate that.
I would have hit all sides of every story.
Exactly.
I'm glad you were able to...
Come out.
What do you do for a living?
I drive trucks.
They're having an event at this park on this day.
So if you can come out,
it would be good for your support.
But if you cannot make it and you have Instagram or Facebook,
you can go to Justice for Moochie and like the page.
I spoke to Kia and Chris.
They told me it was on the news on NBC6.
I didn't get to see it,
but on social media,
everybody was going crazy about it.
They're trying to hope.
You know,
Moochie got a billboard and everybody just talks about it,
but it's a good thing,
man.
They don't have enough evidence against him,
so they can't convict him for that.
It's all a setup.
All they care about is a conviction rate.
If you really look into the case,
you'll see it yourself.
It doesn't take,
like,
a rocket scientist to figure it out.
This is all a setup.
It's a good thing.
It's a blessing.
I'm thankful,
you know,
like,
because just not having your voice heard for so long and not able to tell people,
tell them how you feel or from your standpoint,
it's not no easy experience.
Yo,
thumbs up for that boy Moochie.
Yeah,
boy,
come out and support,
okay?
Come out and support.
Of course.
It's like I explained to you one time I spoke to Kia.
All I'm asking them is for them to believe the facts.
The facts stand alone.
There's no way that you can go around and manipulate it or twist or turn or whatever.
The facts stand firm.
But I have faith and I have belief in good coming from it all.
It's good to have a voice and people speaking out on your behalf and speaking about the truth of who you are,
what you stand for,
and stuff like that.
I need everybody
Just,
you know,
justice for Moochie,
you know?
Free Moochie,
justice for Moochie,
free Moochie.
I was angry.
I was very,
very shocked.
I was very angry.
How dare they put my wife and her murderer's face right next to each other and claim his innocence?
How dare?
I really miss her a lot,
a lot.
We lived for more than 30,
34,
35 years together.
We don't have to say much.
We kind of know what the other people feel and think.
No matter what,
love them,
be kind to them.
If you can't help,
help them.
That's really her motto.
She always volunteered something to help people.
The first one she did was in Cambodia.
She was working at the refugee camp for the United Nations High Commission for Refugees,
helping the Cambodian refugees escaping the Khmer Rouge genocide.
And after that,
she came back to San Francisco.
She was working for the
Southeast Asian Refugee
Resettlement Program.
So she's always volunteering something.
At the time of her death,
she was volunteering for an organization called Insightful Blind,
which is to read the newspaper or articles,
newspaper,
magazine type of thing,
record it,
and to visually impair people to be able to access those news.
As a matter of fact,
that afternoon of the day she was killed,
she was supposed to go there.
The police came and talked to me.
They wanted to question me about how he got a handcuffed key.
So I sat down and talked to him.
I said,
you know,
are you kidding me?
I'm going to give up
30 years of practice to give a client a handcuffed key?
I said,
you better start looking within the jail,
because that's got to be where it came from.
How do you steal a handcuffed key when you're always cuffed?
How do you steal it?
You wait till one of the deputies go to sleep,
and then you do it the other way,
or you take a bone and you tie it to the end of a string,
and you want the dog to bring you the keys,
and that's the way you do it?
That's how we're doing it now to get the jail cuff key?
Broward Sheriff's Office quickly initiated an investigation as to how this happened.
Where did he get the key?
That was never determined.
Was it a deputy?
who was in corrections,
had lost her key a few months before.
The sheriff's office believes that Deontay found a handcuffed key on the ground,
and that's how he undid his handcuffs and got out.
That seems totally unrealistic to me.
It just don't,
oh,
I lost my key.
All right,
we'll just order another key.
That don't happen like that.
It doesn't happen like that,
especially on the floor that he's on.
That's the lockdown floor.
That's where all the murderers and all the terrible people are who have committed crimes are on that floor.
You're not gonna lose a cuff key up there and just let it go.
No,
that ain't gonna happen.
And now newly obtained search warrant records indicate Reziles used his Facebook account while in jail to help coordinate the escape.
Detective Timothy Metz wrote in the warrant application that during multiple jail calls,
Reziles informs people he is speaking with that he occasionally accesses Facebook by using a BSO employee's cell phone to do so.
Now I spoke with Reziles'
attorney Don Williams today.
He said he didn't know if a BSO cell phone was used during the escape.
As for Reziles,
he remains in the Broward County Jail without bond.
There were only two deputies,
by the way,
that were disciplined on this.
And one of them is a guy named Denell Harper.
He was a longtime deputy.
They disciplined him for not calling out Reziles on the ripped pants.
Now his
punishment for this was,
I believe he was dinged eight hours without pay.
And then there was another longtime deputy who apparently did not search
Rosales at the other side properly.
There were not more people disciplined.
I mean,
it was only those two deputies.
At the end of the day,
the big investigation for what went wrong says,
oh,
all these things went wrong,
but no one's actually responsible.
We all got to just take this L.
He escaped and he got away.
Leave it at that.
Let's just charge him.
As far as the internal investigations,
let's just leave that alone.
And they don't work like that there.
They don't work like there at all.
BSO will come after their own.
They will come after their own.
I've seen it several times.
And why they haven't come after their own on this one?
Hmm.
Maybe it's politics.
Sheriff Scott Israel pointed part of the blame at the Broward County Commission,
claiming a lack of funds prevented him from manning the courthouse with as many armed deputies as he would have liked.
He says only 15 deputies were on duty to protect the courthouse at the time of the escape.
I've been battling with Broward County for three years now,
asking for adequate staffing for a courthouse that was understaffed from the day I became Sheriff of Broward County.
This is why people are looking for...
Someone they believe is armed and dangerous.
This is after that traumatic courthouse event.
And that's what you hear from your sheriff,
is they should have given me more money.
Bridge continues with the battle brewing between Sheriff Scott Israel and the county commission.
Today,
Israel demanded more money for his age of agency even before addressing the manhunt.
He actually said that you and the commission care more about money than you do about lives.
It's a blatant outright...
And it's an insult,
but it's a lie,
too.
It doesn't bother me in the least.
It shows me how weak he is.
Why would he talk about money when this is about saving lives and getting this suspect back under their supervision?
The theory is that they need it,
and they wanted more deputies at the courthouse.
Courthouse told them no.
So in theory,
if someone was to escape or an attempt and escape,
then it would show that they need more deputies.
That's all I can say about it.
That's just my theory.
I mean,
why would you help him?
Why would you do it?
You got to have something to gain from it.
I'm telling you,
man,
I was just helping and doing a favor for a favor,
man.
So who's the favor to?
They said they needed to help the guy get the money for the courthouse.
I was just helping him out,
man.
All right.
Are we done?
Yeah,
we're done.
I want to talk to Scott,
man.
That's what I want to talk to.
Scott likes to talk to people who talk the truth.
Hey,
maybe I'll probably reconsider and talk the truth to the big guy,
man.
I love that guy,
Yeah,
yeah.
All right.
When you get a chance and you tell him,
man,
tell him I said I would love to speak with him,
politic with him a little bit,
man.
Even if I could get five minutes out of his time,
I'd just let him talk to him.
I doubt it.
Do I believe that?
I would be skeptical.
I would want to know more.
I mean,
I think that you should always be skeptical in these situations.
Is it true?
We don't know.
There's a lot to that story or whatever,
because a lot of people don't understand the full story and everything behind it or whatever.
But it's a lot to the case and a lot to the matter.
But when it's time for trial,
everything that the people don't know about the whole escape,
the case,
and then everything.
It'd be out for everybody to have an understanding of all that stuff.
Did Dayanti explain to you how he escaped?
I can't.
I can't discuss that with you.
That'd be attorney-client privilege.
Okay.
Put it out,
power.
So what?
So what you doing now?
Honestly,
me and my old girl,
we bumping heads.
So I've been out here on the street,
trying to find us on something.
Well just stay positive,
keep your head up.
Oh yeah,
guys too.
That's it.
Just know,
say,
everything is for a time and a season.
Absolutely.
And when your new season come in,
you gotta be ready to walk through the door.
I'm trying to tell you.
You can't be playing with it.
Yeah.
How it happened was,
I got arrested in like August.
Then I got transferred to the main job,
and I ended up being his roommate.
So I spent four months with him,
and during the four months,
he escaped.
Oh,
everybody know he ain't do it.
Everybody,
that's the word.
We grew up breaking in houses and stuff.
Killing,
we don't kill.
We just want money and material things.
We're not looking for any violence.
How y'all lovely people doing today?
Alright.
I'm Day Day,
better known as Richard.
Moochie's big brother,
Shay Shay's oldest son.
Y'all applause her,
this lady here.
They know everything what's going on.
She did her best to raise all four of her kids.
Yeah.
Let that be known.
Yeah,
let that be known,
because they make it seem like people don't got control of their household.
So this mama did everything she needed to do.
We have to let them know we know how to stand up,
not lean,
sit down,
bend over,
twerk,
do whatever they think.
That's all we good for,
black or white.
You know what I'm saying?
We can't change the color of our skin.
Can my skin speak for me?
I got to speak for my skin.
You come to TV.
It's the same story,
just another face,
another name,
another victim.
And we shouldn't wait for
Netflix or whoever to tell the story before we get serious about this situation.
Because after Moochie,
it's going to be another Moochie.
Another Moochie,
another Moochie.
That's why I tell all them,
my black brothers,
you gotta stand up.
You gotta stand up,
you gotta fight for what you believe for.
You gotta tell them people,
all them dead niggas,
they dead.
All them scared niggas,
That's from back in the day.
day.
There's a whole new generation.
You're another generation of black men.
We ain't folding for all this.
We ain't standing for nothing like that.
Our black women,
we got to protect them all.
We got to protect our kids.
Because when they put you like that,
that's why when somebody touch your family,
you have nothing to lose.
It is what it is.
That's why I say,
all my young black brothers,
anybody,
you got to stand up.
You got to stand up for your family.
You be his judge,
you be his lawyer,
oh Lord,
and you come and you touch and agree with everybody,
that you free him.
You bring justice,
oh Lord,
for the lady that has life that's already been ruined in the name of Jesus.
I touch and agree with everybody here.
We don't all know the facts of this case,
and it's not our job,
but we're here for one purpose.
Because God touched each and every one of our hearts and brought us here today.
In the name of the Father,
Son,
and the Holy Spirit,
we close this thing out and we turn it out in peace.
In the name of Jesus,
amen.
Natalia,
that rally just wrapped up here behind me a few moments ago.
Several supporters of Deontay Rosales say they were here to bring attention to his case because they just cannot believe that he would do something like this.
I already have my own plans what I'm gonna do for you.
If anything should happen,
we just gonna have to keep fighting and keep fighting.
And the more time goes by,
the better I will become.
Action speaks louder than words.
I could show you better than I could tell you.
You just met me.
It's been five months going on six that we've been in each other's life.
But I'm not going anywhere.
Ever.
Yeah,
I hope it's true.
I really feel like I'm too young to be feeling this old.
Like,
I don't even feel like I'm 22.
I feel like I'm fucking 50 years old.
And I had to carry so much weight around.
And it's like...
Yeah.
It's a bigger purpose.
Like,
God has a bigger plan for you.
You're going through this for a reason.
It's not gonna last.
This is not gonna,
this is not your life,
not your destination.
This is just a tunnel that you're going through,
like a dark valley that you're going through,
and you will go through that.
You're going through it now,
and you will come through it,
and it's gonna be very bright.
Yeah,
right.
But how long will you actually be there?
Forever,
until we fight to get you out.
I will be there for you forever until the end.
I love you,
John.
too.
Deontay Rezile's tangled web of alleged accomplices grew early this morning with the arrests of eight people.
He used eight different people to help him escape.
Fast forward another year,
he used eight additional people to help him formulate this criminal enterprise.
33-year-old Crystal Isaacs of Fort Lauderdale had never met Reziles before his escape.
She began writing him letters and visiting him in jail in August 2016.
She's accused of acting as a go-between for Rosales and others,
of passing bribe money onto a detention center.
deputy out of manipulating Rosales'
Facebook page.
His murder case,
the case against him was clearly strengthened by the investigation that our public corruptions unit and the state attorney's office has done over the past year.
And we look forward to the day when prosecution begins.
um,
I heard really really loud noises outside.
It sounded like a football field.
And I opened my eyes a little bit and I seen a tank.
I didn't really know if I was dreaming or I wasn't fully awake.
I heard the door be broken to pieces like they were breaking it down.
And then I heard my brother's voice and he said,
um,
no,
my hands are up,
please don't shoot,
please don't shoot.
You're in some trouble today,
I'll be honest with you.
Your association with
Deontay is...
Problematic.
And I was like,
what the fuck is this?
What is going on?
This is crazy.
I still didn't understand.
He readied my charges,
and I did not understand what he was saying.
Crystal Isaacs is accused of acting as a go-between for Rezyles and others,
of passing bribe money onto a detention deputy,
and of manipulating Rezyles'
Facebook page.
Rezyles gave the deputy a handwritten letter saying that he wanted to get a cell phone into the jail.
The deputy did the right thing.
He came forward.
We initiated a proactive investigation.
And at that point,
we started to monitor him.
We gave him a phone to use,
and we were listening to the phone,
myself and the FBI.
That deputy got him a wiretapped phone,
and investigators say phone calls and text messages trapped eight other suspects in the crime.
Saturday will be one year since his escape,
this Saturday,
one year anniversary.
He brought down eight more people.
On this new thing you've got going on.
Rosales allegedly enlisted the group to help lie and cover for him to authorities.
His current case has to do with trying to get people to lie for him in court.
The operation was dubbed Rico Suave,
deputies say,
because of how Rosales was able to charm others into helping him.
He screwed a lot of people's lives up that conspired and agreed to do things.
So his murder case,
the case against him was clearly strengthened.
By the investigation that our public corruptions unit and the state attorney's office has done over the past year,
and we look forward to the day when prosecution begins.
Sure appear heaven
A judge added 37 new charges to Rezile's record,
bringing the grand total to 70.
He's already being held without bond for the murder and escape charges against him,
so there's really no chance he could be released from jail.
Last year we had
Mr. Rezile's escape and then get apprehended,
which complicated the case or made it harder for him.
And now they have filed a RICO case,
which basically concerns him trying to fabricate an alibi.
According to the affidavit,
Deontay is brought into jail.
Deontay sees there is a new officer on the block,
Mr.
G.
Does Deontay know that Mr.
G is a new officer on the block?
We don't know.
The affidavit knows.
The affidavit says
Deontay knows there's a new officer on the block.
And he wanted to test the new officer.
I was doing my
30-minute check.
I looked directly in his flap to see if he was okay.
And he looked at me.
He was sitting on his bed,
and then he said,
gee,
can you get that for me?
And I said,
what are you talking about?
He was like,
what's on the flap?
I said,
okay,
no problem.
So I took the note,
I put it in my pocket,
and I finished my
30-minute round,
and I went into the control room.
And the note says,
A.
They tell me you're a good guy.
They tell me I can trust you.
So I'm looking at a copy right here of a note that was passed to you on December 6th.
It's basically addressed to you.
He calls you brah,
B-R-A,
and then he basically is stroking your ego and seems to be grooming you to be somebody that he needs to help him.
Is that how you get it too?
Absolutely.
Mr.
G,
according to the affidavits.
takes it to his supervisors and they say,
aha,
they must be psychic too,
because they realize,
hey,
I think,
we think he's testing you out.
So we think you should play along.
They're such psychics.
They didn't know either.
They were all surprised.
Play along.
Maybe we hit the jackpot.
Maybe he's really trying to escape.
So
Mr. G cultivates a relationship with
Deontay.
He doesn't really lay out too much with you.
He just says in this particular letter that he had a phone before.
He calls it a line,
but the phone was taken from him.
And it sounds as if he's laying the groundwork to get a phone brought in,
correct?
So what do we do?
Another one says,
why don't we come up with a plan to put a telephone in his hand?
Our phone.
And he will think he has a private line.
And we're monitoring everything.
So now we're monitoring both the jail phone and his private phone.
What a wonderful country.
Let's do that.
And that's what they did.
So now,
how do we accomplish this task?
Did you see that hot,
smoking,
pretty lady who came to see him the other day?
I think that's his girlfriend.
Yeah,
yeah.
Let's use that pretty girl.
Hello,
hey,
is this Crystal?
Yes.
Um,
Moochie want me to give you something.
What is it?
It's a letter.
And what's your name?
My name is Deputy G.
Deputy?
Yeah.
Oh,
no.
Yeah.
This don't even seem right.
Deputy,
you're not going to arrest me,
are you?
No,
I'm not going to arrest you.
It's nothing to be worried about.
It's nothing to be nervous about.
It's not,
you know,
it's none of that.
I just got to get that to you because it's for you to help him out with his child.
You just got to do what the paper says.
I don't know what it says.
You just got to go ahead and do that.
Okay.
I'm on my way to Brown Mall.
So can we meet up in 30 minutes,
20 minutes?
So when I met with him,
he got off his car and he walked up to me and he goes,
damn,
you are beautiful.
And I said,
thank you.
Then he walked to the front of his car,
kind of leaned on it a little bit,
and he goes,
here,
this is the letter.
And he goes,
I didn't read it.
Crystal reads the letter.
She thinks it's something to do with the ring.
So she took it and walked to the side of her car and read it.
No ring?
What is this?
So she took it to Mr.
G.
What is this?
I was expecting a ring.
And he goes,
um...
So you have the phone?
I was like,
the phone?
You want to use my phone?
I have my phone.
He goes,
no,
you're supposed to give me a phone.
And I said,
I don't know.
He said,
okay,
well,
do you have the money for the phone?
I said,
no,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Deontay never told me anything about money for the phone or nothing like that.
The only thing that Deontay ever asked me for money was...
Money to get the car out of the pound and he goes,
oh,
well,
I guess car must have been cold for phone
That's what he said.
They tried to get crystal to buy the ante phone.
Thank God she didn't somehow they managed and succeeded through some other somebody else or whoever else they worked on to get a phone to Deontay a phone that they had hooked up a
phone that they were monitoring completely
And that was the phone Deontay was calling everybody including Crystal about.
So Mr.
G tells Crystal,
listen,
you didn't buy the phone.
Who wanted you to buy the phone?
Now he managed to get the phone,
but we got to pay the bills.
Then started harassing her for money.
I spoke to him already.
He told you already?
He was like,
hey Crystal,
um...
I paid the phone bill,
so don't worry about it,
and we'll just meet up later on in the week to get the money.
So I picked the money up,
and I said,
okay.
So thank you very much.
He was like,
no problem.
I think it's $35.
Should I give him extra?
I'll see the point of giving him extra.
Okay.
Her judgment was so impaired,
is that at one point she got her mother.
involved because she was unavailable to make the payment to the guard and the guard met with her and of course when the guard would meet with anybody he was recorded.
She said to me Deonte needs commissary can you take her to the jail because she's busy she had to go to work I said yeah then she calls me later on and she said don't worry you don't have to go to the jail the deputy
It's gonna be over here at the mall.
You can give him the money and he'll do it.
Okay.
You look just like Kristen.
You do.
Oh,
she look like you.
Let me say that.
Oh,
it's like her dad.
How you doing?
I'm fine.
Alright,
um...
Thank you.
Alright.
Appreciate it.
Alright,
you're welcome.
As soon as I gave him the money,
he goes,
Oh,
yeah,
here's the phone that I bought.
I said phone.
I don't know anything about the phone.
Yeah,
yeah,
I got just the phone.
I'll give you.
Don't show me.
All I know is that you've got some money to put food for him to eat.
So we're all gonna feed him.
And that's all.
He's my friend and I want to feed him.
That's all I know.
Okay,
no problem.
Just like Chris do.
So her mom contributing $30,
supposedly,
for a phone bill for Deonte.
Her mom got charged too.
Yes.
Yes,
the mother.
That's how it normally goes,
right?
They go after your mother or your wife or your kids.
So yeah,
I was targeted because they wanted to hurt him.
I feel heartbroken.
I feel like they tore us apart from each other.
I don't think it's right.
As pretty as she is,
she's very feeble and very insecure and easily influenceable.
When guys go to jail...
They tell you they're going to marry you tomorrow.
Because obviously you have more to offer them than they have to offer you.
But don't get so wrapped up.
You have a child.
You have your own life.
You have a career.
Maybe she was seeking love.
And he's very,
what's the word I'm looking for?
What do they call men that,
not a gentleman,
but men that sweep women off their feet with their words.
That's the kind of person he is.
I haven't gotten everything yet,
but the allegation is that he called up a number of his friends on the cell phone and discussed with them,
creating an alibi for himself that he was out of town in Georgia when the murder occurred.
Okay,
I know he was in Georgia from the 3rd.
And then I came back on the 9th when I had picked you up from your doctor's appointment.
Wait,
hold on.
I got to miss the work?
I don't know what day it is,
but it's so shit.
I'm going to need you to do that for me,
shit.
If you do got to miss work,
whatever you're going to make,
that day I'll pay you.
His effort to craft the alibi.
was part of what led police to believe even more firmly that he had committed the Halliburton-Sue murder.
He doesn't come out and say to people I want you to lie for me.
If you read the letters and you listen to the calls,
he's very sophisticated about how he goes about it because you know asking somebody to lie for you is a big thing.
That's not the way he goes about it.
He says no no I I need you to tell them this because then I'll get to go home.
I'm going to really need your help,
OK?
OK.
I already spoke to them,
and I spoke to everybody.
I'm going to need you there as a witness,
basically,
because I need you to just tell them about me knowing that I was in Georgia because we stayed in contact on social media and on the phone and stuff,
whatever.
I need you for that reason.
OK.
But I'll pay you for it.
I got you,
but I really need you to do that for me.
He had convinced a new girlfriend with whom he had spent.
no time out of jail but she joined him in this effort anyways go on my page you want me to go on your page yeah i need you to go in there go all the way back to 2014 which part where in um 2014 you want september now
go back up to the one when i say we might be leaving georgia early might be leaving atlanta early um
things went good with the power of the father yeah that one i just don't want to get wrong interpretations i need you to delete that for me you said delete it yeah delete the post from off my wall okay just
delete it
Okay.
If he was in the
Atlanta area,
it was before the murder.
And he was back in South Florida before the murder.
They did some sophisticated cell phone tracking on his cell phone and they were able to show,
quite frankly,
I think it coming down the expressway as he made his way south.
So they bolstered.
The Davey investigation and the BSO investigation by this whole new cell phone analysis,
placing his cell phone in South Florida when this happened,
placing his cell phone not far from the murder scene.
So this whole new plan of trying to create a defense has actually resulted in the murder case being strengthened.
Not only by the evidence of he's trying to fabricate a defense,
but physical evidence in terms of cell phone analysis.
The fact that he had escaped and gotten caught and is still trying to manipulate circumstances,
I think,
again,
goes to support why someone who's just committing a burglary would kill somebody.
This is a guy who will do anything to get himself...
out of trouble.
Whether he did the homicide or not,
it's sort of irrespective to this,
he did sucker these people into committing serious crimes on his behalf.
You know,
they're all going to be in real trouble.
And that ability to be persuasive,
to be manipulative,
to be charming,
and to be unconcerned about the ramifications of that for this other person is consistent with psychopathy.
We call this officially antisocial personality disorder.
which in many ways misleads people because it sounds like these folks are loners but in fact they love people you know um that doesn't mean he committed the homicide but he definitely did this you know uh this uh sort of scenario i hate to admit this his faces are really cute he
have this what i call puppy eyes have a little white eye underneath it and if you're looking Looking down and looking up at you is a puppy expression.
Face is round.
Disproportionate big eyes,
big forehead.
Those are the human baby future that if you look at Disney character,
they all have that characteristic and evoke the emotion.
Oh my God,
I hope to embrace you because you're so cute.
He carried that.
I'm sure he knew that since he was little and he can use that expression and his talk into manipulating people into what he want them to do.
To be honest with you,
a lot of people are going to jail for some of the things they're doing after and not even really the crime itself that they're in jail for.
And this happens to a lot of our clients that we represent.
They can't help themselves.
They get inside jail.
They get on the jail phone and they just they.
I mean,
desperate men do desperate things.
You gotta realize the things that I go through and I endure on a day-to-day basis,
like,
people don't realize the mental,
emotional,
or,
like,
the spiritual torment that I have to endure.
And it's just those things that just powered up,
and I'm like,
I have nowhere to turn.
Like,
it's nothing.
I've tried to do everything.
I exhausted every remedy that I have presented before me,
and it's just like,
I was frustrated.
I was tired,
like...
Mm.
And,
um...
I didn't ask you before,
but where were you on the day of the murder?
I can't even.
I don't even,
to be honest with you,
I don't even remember this day.
Like,
I can't.
There's nothing significant that I can recall to think of.
Hmm.
Yeah,
I understand.
Burglary of a dwelling is 15 years,
so you got two of those.
If you got two of those,
that's 30,
right?
You got an escape,
that's 15,
so now you got 45 years,
right?
Now you got a RICO charge.
Just the RICO charge is 30 years,
along with there's a bunch of substantive charges.
So before you even get to a conviction of a murder charge,
he's potentially serving 75 to 100 years in prison.
It's a tough defense,
yeah.
but now what it's really what it boils down to now is saving his life.
They were like,
don't smile,
don't look at him,
keep your hands to yourself.
So I told the officer,
I said,
I cannot tell you I'm not gonna smile.
Like,
I'm gonna start blushing when I see him.
But he was like,
it's okay,
just don't give him any eye contact and don't like,
pick your hands up or do anything weird.
So.
I don't know if you see it,
like when I,
you know why I always like limp a little bit when I'm walking?
They put this electric,
a big electric monitor on my leg.
Like if I do something,
it'll shock me,
like I could defecate on myself,
urinate.
or stuff like that but you know they laid out rules like okay you can't look in her direction you can't do this or whatever so i don't want to do anything or look at how direction is in they go together and she gets nervous and she gets scared but i got to see her out of the corner
She looked so beautiful.
Her hair got longer,
everything.
I was overjoyed when
I seen him.
I felt happy.
I didn't think he was going to look that good,
but he looked really good.
I felt the vibrations.
I felt the feeling that she was transferring off.
And,
like,
she had this beautiful innocence about her.
And then I was just thinking,
I'm like,
wow,
like,
I was hurt.
Because,
like,
it's like you being strapped and you being tied down or whatever.
I mean,
you're watching some...
or some people harming your wife or your kids or whatever,
and you can't do nothing about it,
it kind of hurts you in your heart because knowing what she's going through or whatever,
it's just a bad feeling.
Judge,
if we believe our truth,
then clearly both Crystal and his mom are not part of any underlying conspiracy that may have been cooked up by Mr.
Desarte's results.
Deontay's case is the master case.
Massive.
It's several cases rolled in one.
There is the murder case and then there whatever other small burglaries was involved in it.
So we're trying to extricate ourselves from that case and take care of Crystal's case and her mom's case separately.
The conspiracy,
whatever it is,
we're not part of it.
And I'm proving to you,
we're not part of anybody's conspiracy.
That goes to the strength of the case.
Next,
I'm saying because we're not
part of any conspiracy you need to give us bam why should we sit around while you're trying to figure out are we with this conspiracy with that conspiracy leave her out
I enjoyed representing him,
but I knew he was impatient,
and I knew that once I got involved in that other murder trial,
that he was not going to be satisfied,
and I don't know that I would be either,
with me saying,
I'll see you in a couple of years,
because I'm in court on another murder case.
Mike Orlando,
he's a very dedicated lawyer,
and he's also assisted by Alari,
and they formed a very good defense team.
Because it sits on an island.
That's an island.
What do you mean an island?
The whole community.
This is the whole community here.
Oh,
I see.
So it sits on this island,
and you can't get in.
Yeah,
it's like a peninsula.
Right.
So the whole thing is surrounded by canals.
So,
I mean,
I don't understand.
let's face it,
it can't be over here.
No.
So they're either saying it had to be here or this side.
Right.
Somebody was alleging like he would get a suit on or something and go through neighborhoods and all that.
So,
I mean,
that's not the same as dredging through a backyard.
Right.
So you can't have it both ways.
You can't claim that his M.O.
is going to sue.
Going in a suit,
you know,
looking like a nice,
proper person.
And then when no one's home,
breaking in versus,
you know,
trudging through everybody's backyard discreetly.
Yeah.
I mean,
I'm not sure where all that information comes from,
but I know that it was conveyed to me.
Yeah.
It might have been through Don.
It could have been.
I think Don was saying that,
too,
that he was,
how does he get through the backyard?
Like,
did he go knock on the door to see if someone was home?
or anything like that.
He was like,
well,
no,
he has an MO in some of his other burglaries.
And I was like,
OK,
but the MO doesn't fit this one,
right?
And he was like,
no.
I was like,
OK,
that's good for us,
right?
He was like,
yeah,
OK.
So,
you know,
he would have had to come in through those yards all the way down and jump all those gates.
I find it hard to believe.
That someone would have went,
killed someone,
and after they killed someone,
come up that backside of their way,
running,
without leaving a shred of evidence,
jumping out and coming out through one of these gates.
I don't know.
It's like this whole incident,
it's just been one impossible after another.
Down this way,
down that area,
about four or five houses down,
is the crime scene.
So they would have had to either go through about four to five backyards to run through there in order to come out of these bushes to get out of there if they were going off.
To avoid water.
And you still got to run through people's yards.
The African-American dude is running through here.
Ain't no way in the world.
Ain't nobody over here.
Ain't nobody that he going through their yards.
ain't gonna call the police at that time of day in that neighborhood even if you got in that way i mean you're gonna get grass you're gonna get the stick of bird stuff on your shoes some of this stuff would have either been in the house so the suggestion is they were in the vehicle they had to be now
are you in a position to give any type of opinion as to how the perpetrators would have been able to enter into the westbridge community on september 8
on or about September 8th,
2014.
All I can say is they did come in through the Kate house in a position where I would have seen him.
He knows what the client looks like and he did not see him there that morning.
You know,
so that's,
I mean,
that's probably the...
It wasn't like,
well,
I don't know,
I wasn't paying attention.
It was like,
no,
I did not see him.
Hi.
Sorry to bother you.
My name is John McVeigh.
I'm a private investigator.
Did you live here in 2014?
2014,
I did.
You did.
OK.
So
I'm hired by the criminal defense attorney on the homicide that happened down the street.
OK.
Your white fence that goes along here,
was that here then stuck into the water like that?
It was.
And was the guy behind you,
the hedge,
the same way too?
The hedge behind.
Yeah,
that separates your property from the next one.
That also has a fence.
That's actually my hedge.
Oh,
it is here?
It may have been higher.
Okay,
all right.
But it was there.
Okay,
all right.
Were you home during that day?
Do you remember?
Because I didn't see you ever interviewed by the police.
Or at least anybody from this address.
Yeah,
I was here.
You were?
I work out of the house.
Oh,
okay.
I'm here 90%.
Okay.
So like you're gonna talk about burglaries like look this house has the exact same door as the one that Deonte is accused of kicking in and getting through the house so you're gonna bypass this house to go three more lots this
fence looks old too so it doesn't make sense
That's,
if you're looking through that backyard,
that's a straight shot from the road.
That would make more sense coming that way than it would be coming down that way,
down the canal road.
He was concerned about a hole in the fence that people can get through.
I can jump right over this.
The hole had nothing to do with it.
There's a bunch of holes in the fence.
I don't need it,
you just get up over here,
jump in.
And then you're right by the street.
Well,
logically,
they're gonna have to say he came this way.
So where's he parked his car?
All the way down to the park,
which is probably a quarter of a mile,
third of a mile.
So what we're going to do is we're going to drive out of here the shortest route from West Ridge Community to where his phone hits off the cell tower at 1228,
which is position number 25.
So we're right here at the victim's house.
So we're going to go out here,
drive north.
To 595 and then go east on 595 to State Road 7.
Speed limit is 45 on this road.
So we're at about 11 minutes,
11.04 to get into the area,
which is basically where we were.
If at 12.13 he was grabbing the camera and out the door and he sprinted probably from the house to his car and then basically didn't really have any traffic
issues,
yeah he could have got to this location.
There's the point of entry where someone kicked in the sliding glass door.
So,
Deontay Resilis has a number of outstanding charges related to burglaries.
There's one that happened in the city of Boca Raton,
Florida on November
5th, 2013.
And the thing that's interesting about this case is the entry to the residence.
Is through what appears to be a backsliding glass door where it's kicked out.
There's a small entrance.
So he clearly went to the back of the house,
kicked in that glass,
and then went in.
In all of those cases,
he focuses on the master bedroom.
And he steals jewelry because that's what he takes on all the cases.
You want to see pictures of some of the stuff on his phone?
Yeah,
let me give you some pictures.
Hold on.
Where do I have them?
Oh.
All from his phone.
This is what he steals.
He focuses on master bedrooms and he steals jewelry because then he sells it at the swap shop.
Searches for homes,
fancy homes.
Oh,
here's more pictures of jewelry.
More pictures of him with all the money.
Fancy homes.
In two of the burglaries that he has,
he pulled alarm panels off the wall and in one of them,
Put them in a tub with water in it.
And another one,
he put it in the sink,
in the sink of the bathroom,
and left the water running,
just like he did with Mrs.
Sue.
If you see in these photographs,
there's close-ups,
the water's running,
and lo and behold,
here's the alarm box.
So whoever committed this burglary,
who we believe was Deontay,
because we now know that the faucet handle has a blood stain on it that implicates him,
Deontay must have cut his hand.
Somewhere during the burglary,
and then placed this alarm box in the master bedroom sink,
and then touched the faucet when he turned it on,
leaving the bloodstain.
So it's extremely similar in
Jill Sue's case,
which clearly is probably some kind of means to disable the alarm in case there's a battery backup,
things like that.
Their argument,
in my opinion,
doesn't hold because it's not a unique way of committing a burglary.
To go into a home,
break a window,
disarm the alarm,
happens in every burglary case.
Most homes in South Florida have glass doors that can be easily broken.
Most homes have alarms.
Sometimes they have an independent battery.
And the best way of messing up a battery,
you don't even have to be an expert on it,
is making it wet.
It's not a unique thing.
They don't feed her.
Some Jamaican officer who has been giving her a hard time,
when she went around and said everybody else purposely did not feed Christo.
I truly believe they're trying to break her.
I really believe they're trying to break her spirit.
That's why I'm fighting so hard that we get the depositions so I can get out on bail.
I don't know how much longer she can take it.
And the new hiccup on the
Rico case is that it looks like Crystal Isaacs is going to give a proffer against our client.
So in exchange for this proffer,
her bond is going from,
let's see,
$250,000,
$310,000,
$20,000,
$30,000,
$40,000,
$440,000,
$450,000,
$470,000,
$470,000 to...
$10,000.
Oh,
wow.
So,
and they're going to try to say that's not a benefit to Crystal in exchange for testifying against Deontay,
but...
It's not a benefit to get out of jail.
A bond of $470,000 versus a bond of $10,000 is a big difference.
If I pled guilty,
what would that mean for Deontay?
It would not be good for him.
That would mean another person is against him.
That's what that means.
That means that everything that they accuse me of,
and they're accusing Deontay of doing with me,
I would be admitting like,
yeah,
it's true.
They want me to help them hang him.
They want me to say he's a bad person.
He's a manipulator.
He's dangerous.
That's what they want.
We'll set Crystal Isaac for October
4th. I'm going to call that a change of plea.
We'll be optimistic.
If it doesn't resolve on that date,
there's a very good chance that that'll be going over to judgment.
It's huge.
Hey,
Mom.
So what you told them?
Nothing.
I raised hap,
you know.
I got a little bit upset inside because it,
you know,
was some drama or whatever.
But nothing.
I'm here.
I have to go straight to Fritz.
You have to go straight to Fritz?
Yes.
You can't come here?
No.
She gave me strict instructions.
She said I have to go to St.
to Fritz's house right now.
And over the weekend,
I have to stay inside until Monday because I wasn't,
I didn't get release in time to go across the street to,
you know,
meet with the ladies.
So.
Oh my God.
So,
so you can't even get no clothes?
No,
I can't.
Not until Monday.
Of course I'm happy for it.
Why wouldn't I be?
I'm happy that she's home because.
I know it wasn't easy for her because I know she couldn't,
at first she possibly couldn't think of how the hell I'm going to survive in jail or how I'm going to go through with it.
And then I felt like it was a point in time like she probably hates me now.
She doesn't want nothing to do with me because I'm like,
oh,
she probably feels like everybody else fucked me and all that other stuff.
But I said,
until I hear it from her,
until she tells me otherwise or whatever,
that's still my fiancée.
That's still who I love.
That's really fascinating to see that he did that.
without them having met in person,
you know,
all through contact,
through the correctional facility.
And again,
I think that speaks to,
you know,
his charm,
incredibly sophisticated charm with women,
to be able to manage to do that.
As far as her,
I mean,
you could hear a little bit of the bewilderment herself,
I think,
that there's a little piece of her that feels like she got charmed in there somewhere,
too,
and that what she's doing or what she did doesn't make a whole hell of a lot of sense.
I feel a lot of sympathy for Crystal.
You know,
she did herself a lot of damage.
She looks like she's a good person.
Probably would have done very well.
But her life has taken a real negative turn.
And,
you know,
whatever else he may or may not have done,
Deontay is responsible for that.
They made an offer for
Crystal to plead guilty.
For the two years or so she's been in jail,
that will be time served.
We're done with the case.
If we plead guilty,
essentially,
officially would be like pleading guilty,
but you plead no contest.
If you plead no contest...
If the judge withholds adjudication,
then it does not enter as a guilty plea for purposes of being able to avoid being a convicted felon.
And if after two years of fighting and recognizing the struggles it took to just get here,
if that's an option you would like,
I,
as an attorney,
I'll fight for that and that will be part of what's on the table.
And then the decision is yours.
Taking the two years time search,
it means that I won't be able to talk to Deontay.
They want me to stay away from him.
And that means that my license and everything that I worked so hard for would be in vain.
Because that means I'm guilty,
and that would be a convicted felon.
And it's not going to be a good look for me.
It's going to be very bad.
So.
We did not charge you with anything that we couldn't prove either through documents or tapes.
Why can't I see the video before trial?
Because it might have been corrupted.
Have you seen the video?
Yes,
I saw it before.
I tried to copy it over and over and over again.
And our IT thinks it's because we tried to extract it so many times,
now the video won't play.
This is funny.
What do you want?
Okay,
if you want to see the video,
then that's it.
That's the end of it.
I'll go back and get ready for trial.
I don't care.
I just want you to know that if we go to trial and you're convicted and afterwards you go,
I didn't know about it.
I didn't know that I was looking at this.
I'm going to say,
you know what,
judge?
That's bullshit.
And he's going to sentence you.
Then you're going to be going through the appellate process.
That's why I asked you,
what is it you want to do with your life?
You were in jail for two and a half years.
Your son was what,
18?
Now he's what,
21 or so?
You're not our interest.
I don't care about you.
I would never,
I would never be involved in anything like that.
I'm not that type of person.
Crystal.
I've listened to the tapes and that's not true.
What's not true?
What you just said.
What?
Like what?
All the charges that I have brought here were all based on the tapes.
Here's what I would recommend.
We'll send you the plea offer in writing.
We'll give you two weeks,
then that offer is going to expire at the end of the two weeks.
There will not be another offer.
Okay.
And we're just going to go forward at that point and,
you know...
You'll get to see the show.
I
didn't like that.
I didn't like it.
I don't feel like it should have ever happened.
Um,
I feel like I was in a cave.
With sharks.
It was just something that should have never happened.
I didn't understand the purpose.
They tried to scare me.
And when I asked them about the tape,
the tape that would have proved that this man actually asked me for a phone and money to buy the phone,
the tape is corrupt,
and this is what the prosecutor,
well,
the tape is corrupt.
It's corrupt.
So then what are you going to do?
What are you going to do then?
This is what happened in the little room.
What are you going to do?
We just won't use it in trial.
Is that okay?
This is my evidence.
I want my evidence.
I said that prosecutor that's working there,
you could slap her and don't even feel sorry.
She's a bitch from hell.
She lies her ass off in there.
You want to hear all that shit she's telling the judge?
A whole pile of lies,
man.
This bitch got me out here for two years and can't work.
Got my daughter in jail for nothing.
I'm not nice to them.
I'm telling you,
I'm not nice to anybody anymore.
I'm not nice.
I'm just not fucking nice because they fucked me over like this.
And they fucked up my child.
And they did a lot of damage in my life and my kids'
life.
I do not have any respect.
I never did like the police from day one.
But now I even hate them more.
I'm seriously,
I hate them even more now.
Because they fucked up my life and my daughter's life.
And that's the reason why everybody hates them.
You think anybody likes them?
If I pled guilty,
it would not be good for him.
But what other choice do I have?
And I really don't know what to do at this point.
So I spend the rest of my life in prison,
or I take the two years time served.
I don't know.
It's a hard pill to swallow.
He ain't gonna marry her.
I agree.
Thank you so much.
Okay,
and my understanding is you'd like to resolve your case today,
is that correct?
Yes.
Alright,
you're going to be pleading to counts 2,
3,
and 13.
And the agreement is that it's going to be an adjudication,
802 days time served with credit for the full time.
Is that your understanding of the state's offer?
Yes.
The counts that you're going to be...
to today are count two which is a conspiracy RICO that's punishable by up to 30 years prison count three bribery of a public servant that's punishable by up to 15 years prison count 13 tampering with a witness involving a life or capital felony that's punishable by life in prison you understand the maximum penalty you're looking at yes ma'am how are you playing to these charges it's
guilty not guilty or no contest
There's three options?
Well,
yes,
but is it a negotiated guilty?
Yes,
your honor,
that was the state's offer.
Okay,
so if you'd like to resolve your case,
then it would be a guilty.
Okay,
guilty.
All right,
I find the defendant is alert and intelligent.
The plea is entered freely and voluntarily with a knowing and intelligent waiver of rights with the assistance of an attorney with whom she's satisfied.
I'm going to accept the guilty plea.
We feel like a lot of burden came off of us today.
It's been a long journey.
We're not really happy with everything.
We didn't get what we wanted,
but in life you don't get everything you want.
So we just have to settle somewhere.
At this point,
we're settled really at the bottom,
but,
you know.
And you,
Crystal?
I really don't have anything much to say.
I really don't.
You look upset.
She's upset.
Because in addition to all of this,
the prosecutor today,
after they make us plead guilty just to get the hell out of here and get it over with,
then he walks up to her and he's taunting her.
Oh,
he's not going to marry her.
He's not going to marry her.
So this pisses her off.
Because,
you know,
the whole point of this arrest for the past two and a half years was because she says,
I'm going to marry Dante.
Because of this.
That's the big,
that's it in a nutshell.
That's the big issue.
They're worried about the wrong things.
We're going over to the pretrial office right now.
We're going to take this monitor off our leg and then we're going to go to the beach.
And then tonight I'm going fishing with my son.
I could think of a few better things to do,
but I'm gonna just do that,
you know,
just cuz I could for the prosecutor
But uh,
okay.
I'm just running off my mouth.
I could think of nicer things to do But right now me and my daughter were going to the beach
I got in contact with the founder of Dropcam,
and I actually spoke to him last night on the phone.
His name's Greg Duffy.
The interesting thing is,
the motion detection,
and when the camera gets shut off,
would have sent still pictures of the last motion to him by email.
Oh,
really?
wow.
So he said that the last motions would have been by email,
which he never says that,
which is which again is leading everything up to this whole camera thing and the death and and him just checking is all fabricated.
So why would you fabricate that?
Well,
to me,
clearly would be.
You know more than what you're telling us.
He happens to check the camera at the exact same time the bad guy is pulling the camera down.
The exact same time.
Which,
that is an unbelievable coincidence.
All the timeline stems from him.
So if it stems from him,
if we take the video away,
then where's the timeline?
Everything comes from the premise of him seeing a video,
but we don't have that video.
So,
without that video,
what do we have?
no,
I got in contact with the founder of Dropcam.
His name's Greg Duffy.
So I spoke with him last night.
Now,
the only caveat to this whole thing is is that he does not want to participate in anything.
He doesn't want to be subpoenaed.
He doesn't want his personal information,
etc.,
etc.
So he went on.
I went on to ask him about,
you know,
how the camera works and things like that.
I'm assuming that Nanyo had an email notification because he makes in his statement that he got emailed regarding a disconnect.
Yeah.
So...
The interesting thing is,
when the camera gets shut off,
would have sent still pictures of the last motion to him by email.
Oh,
really?
So if this person walked up where he claims and undid the camera,
there'd be a snapshot of that,
which he never says that.
The other thing I think we have to look at is this.
Nanyo never says anything about the other camera.
They were both drop cams.
What did he say about the other camera,
Ayati?
Do you remember?
That nothing happened on it.
Yeah.
And he didn't get anything from the other camera.
And they don't believe anything really happened there.
So nothing.
Right.
But again,
that goes against what Dropcam's saying.
Because he would have been notified by email.
And he would have gotten a still shot.
If someone came up and disconnected that camera.
Which again is leading everything up to...
This whole camera thing and the death and him just checking is all fabricated.
They don't seem to want me,
but they won't admit.
I must be some kind of creature if there haven't been.
Having a hard time in this crazy town.
Having a hard time.
There's no love to be.
They could have gotten a warrant for his emails.
They could have seen the email that supposedly notified him of it being disconnected.
And they could have checked if that.
Email showed the still shot of the last person to disconnect the camera or whatever the last motion was.
And they didn't.
It's again a lot of these officers just,
oh just trust us.
We'll just trust him and then you just trust us and don't worry that somebody's liberty.
And actually in this case,
life,
actual life is on the line because if we lose,
he'll be executed by the state of Florida.
if you don't have a subscription service you're only able to see live video it's not going to be recorded up to three hours so hold on your snapshots it's not it's not going to be the video but only snapshots of what happened three hours ago so wait a minute so i
i want to i want to i want to because i'm i'm kind of confused so if if i don't have if if my trial period ends right then i have up to three hours to see snap snapshots
Yep.
I asked him,
if I was law enforcement and I called you guys and I asked you guys for this information,
what would you tell me?
They said exactly.
He can see not the video footage,
but still shots of everything he saw three hours prior.
But we definitely have to see and pinpoint at what time that he actually did call.
I mean,
he could have,
and then at which point we could argue that they were just negligent and not.
They could have got it within three hours and they didn't get it.
Right.
They interviewed
Dropcam that afternoon.
Somebody called Dropcam.
There's a report of it.
One of the detectives,
one of the officers,
I think it was like 1-45.
So it's shortly after the murder.
I think the only big mistake that the office made is that they never pressed
Mr. Su.
They never pressed him.
And they didn't because he was spoon feeding them slowly his son.
Can I speak to you one more thing that kind of focus on you?
Sure.
He cover his face,
okay?
My son cover his face.
And then next thing you know,
he put a towel or something on top of the camera.
That was why you...
That's where we are in.
So,
I know that is the reason why initially I suspect...
I suspect this person
I saw in the mosque,
maybe him,
because he tried to pull the plank on me.
Why would he say that?
Have you ever done that?
I've thrown shit,
like,
over the camera.
Have you ever put something around your face,
messing around?
No,
I haven't.
And your mom saw it and said,
oh,
you're silly or whatever?
No.
Sure about that?
Yeah.
Put something on my face?
A cover up my face?
You sure about that?
Yeah.
So what did happen?
Because the son says that never happened.
Dad says that happened.
And that's how he believed that it was his son,
because that happened.
But son says,
no,
that conversation never happened.
Red flag?
Red flag.
But every time it happened,
he kept going back to the fact that my son,
my son did it,
my son could have done it.
He kind of infers without coming across as saying,
My son did it.
There's a lot of inferences.
He's the only one that knew the camera was up there.
Because both of them being unplugged indicate that they know this camera.
Well,
let me ask you that.
Who knows where they secured it?
My son.
He also referenced that he gave his son like a yellow envelope with all the bank accounts and all that stuff on there.
I sealed them up in an envelope and said,
this envelope,
to hear something happen,
open it.
Just leave it.
I'm not sure if the envelope will be opened or not.
So he gave information like that as well,
like almost like providing not necessarily,
I mean,
almost in a way like a motive.
So my opinion is he was not protective of the son.
Let's put it that way.
He made statements to the detectives,
like I previously stated,
that,
you know,
If he did this,
I can accept it.
I would accept the truth that he did it,
but before that,
we need to make sure that everything is done fairly.
And he just kind of spit-foomed them and gave them enough information to get them out of his room and into the other interrogation room.
I mean,
the theory could be,
if Nanyo committed the murder,
he might know there's not enough evidence.
to convict his son,
but there's enough to have doubt for him that he didn't do it.
I just find that strange,
that from A to B to C to D to E to F to G,
everything is covered.
Everything is fine.
As far as me having a witness with me,
coming back to the home at a certain time,
calling in at a certain time,
getting my son involved at a certain time.
Listen,
it could have all happened that way.
But if it did,
then it was perfect.
It was perfect.
And as I said before,
nothing's perfect in a murder case.
And that's just kind of planned.
Coincidence that he's there 930 to 1130,
and no burglar comes in at that time.
And just they happen to come after he leaves.
Cooking hall,
and I saw this figure with white.
How type of thing,
how about his face?
My memory is probably not very good because it's just a grain of salt.
He happens to check the camera at the exact same time the bad guy is pulling the camera down.
The exact same time.
That is an unbelievable coincidence.
He should have played a lot on the same night.
He should have played it all week.
He should have played the cash flow every day.
Because how,
how can you...
OK,
just I'm just going to look into my phone.
Oh,
by the way,
I'm at work.
Oh,
I'm bored.
Let me check the cameras.
Oh,
what is this?
I see somebody breaking in.
Oh,
what's the chances?
Then the subscription ends,
and conveniently everything is just gone,
and there's no,
now there's no proof of anything.
That whole part is troubling.
When's the last time you saw your mom?
This morning,
around probably like 9.45 right before I left.
I said,
hey,
good work.
See you later.
What was her response?
She was sitting in the living room with the other camera.
There's another camera,
and probably my dad could watch her.
She was just reading a book in the living room.
When she come to bed,
my impression...
The situation was just about 8 o'clock,
8.30 or something like that.
And then I kind of dozing off,
on and off,
and finally I wake up around 9,
9.10 or something like that.
You got up and she was still in bed?
She was still asleep.
Asleep?
She was totally asleep.
Danielle makes the statement that at 8.30,
Jill comes to bed and she sleeps.
And she was in bed until he left at 11.30.
At 9.45,
Justin leaves the house,
makes the statement that his mom's on the couch.
So why would the contradiction be so vastly different?
If Jill was on the couch or in bed,
why would they be basically telling opposite stories?
And granted,
two people standing next to each other could see the same thing and tell you different stories.
But they're going to tell you that,
yeah,
there was one person here.
If he was in any way involved,
it does show an opportunity to have had alone time with her,
to have done this more than enough time to do this in the span of two hours.
There's clearly enough time after his son leaves to possibly have committed a crime,
to stage the crime to make it look like a burglary,
and then leave and go to work to set up an alibi.
And when he gets to work,
he then uses the drop cam as a reference to claim that someone has broken into the house.
And instead of calling the police to investigate,
he calls his son to go to the house.
Why not call the front guard gate,
where there's an armed security guard,
or call the Davie Police Department,
who is less than a mile away,
that would have been there a lot quicker than either him or Justin leaving their job and going back to the house?
Two reasons why he could be
sending his son.
One is stupidity,
because you're sending your son into a possible burglar who's in your house.
Or two,
he's trying to establish a timeline.
And he's allowing his son to find his mother dead.
And we know that Nanyo was nowhere near the house at the time.
There's an interest in saying that he saw a person at a particular time,
because it would change the time of death.
And that's why the police did not investigate before that time.
Because he's limited the time to after he saw the person on camera.
Did you see any other injuries to her besides her neck?
I wanted to say her face was a little bit bruised or something,
but I don't know if that's from like,
you know,
the rigor mortis.
I don't even know.
You're not going to find rigor mortis in a
15-minute window or a
20-minute window and probably not even a 30-minute window.
By the naked eye,
the person isn't going to notice it,
but Justin did notice it.
And if Justin noticed it,
it had to be pretty substantial.
The other thing I thought was interesting is,
and if you remember this,
about 1228 p.m.,
Justin shows up at the house,
okay?
They bring the canine in within about an hour.
Not even that,
I think it was.
Now,
canines will search for people and they'll do tracks.
So if someone went in or out a door and then down the grass around the lot,
you know,
through the bushes or whatever it is,
the dog's going to pick up on that,
even if there's other people around.
Okay.
So the canine,
which I thought was very specific because.
He didn't pick up any track of anybody leaving the residence.
This is showing me that nobody left the house after the murder.
All right,
well.
We're going to have you here.
You're going to start.
Okay,
thanks.
So,
what did you see?
When I clicked in,
I saw this figure with this face covered with some kind of white cloth.
And the camera image is not very good,
kind of fuzzy,
but I could see this figure.
The face is covered with some kind of white cloth,
except around the eye is a belt like this,
straight.
And this is totally black.
So you're basically,
you're motioning that you could see the eyes.
I could not see the eye.
Well,
I don't mean the eye area.
The eye area is pitch black.
What do you mean pitch black?
Because it's a dark band.
It's what?
It's a band of darkness in contrast to the white thing he's wearing on his face.
And you said you had an opportunity to look at your statement that you gave to the police?
Yes.
And now the detective in that statement asked you if the person was black or white,
correct?
He said it's a black and white,
yes.
And you said white,
correct?
I wasn't sure if I'm mistaken his question is a whitish person or a white human being.
But I just my impression was he's whitish because of the mask in his face.
and also
He shows his white.
The person I know,
you said a male or whatever,
could you tell if it was a male?
Is it a male or female?
I think it's a male.
Okay.
Rather skinny.
How old does this male look?
20ish.
Okay.
Looks like,
doesn't look like very old to me.
Okay.
I can't see the face so I can tell,
but from the body language that he's not shrugging,
you know,
moving body is rather smooth.
You tell white male,
black male,
or?
Looks like a white.
Okay.
And I think he understood the question,
and I think he,
who he saw in 2014 was a white person.
If there was any indication that the person was black,
he would have said black.
And then in the...
And he asked his son,
you know,
was that you?
He would not confuse his son for black person.
I just think they probably...
They coached him.
Yeah,
they coached him.
They coached him.
And that's the position they took.
But at least we know what their tactic is going to be.
I don't think it's going to come across well.
Plus,
we can impeach him.
We'll just play that portion.
And the jurors are going to be like...
You clearly said a white person.
Yeah.
So that part's good.
It's on video.
Then,
of course,
we find out some personal stuff about him.
He got remarried,
what,
a couple years?
He said in 2017 he got remarried,
so three years after the fact.
And then she,
well,
she's currently,
she's 30 years old.
She's 30 years old.
He's 68.
There's a
38-year difference.
She has a son.
We found out Justin moved after this.
Somehow he's not in the house anymore.
He's still living in the house where this happened with his new wife,
which is also kind of odd.
I don't know when he would have started dating her,
but at least for a while.
Dating or seeing her?
Yeah.
I don't know.
I wonder if that's why he went to the office that morning.
Could be.
I don't know.
So on the date in question,
September 8th,
2014,
when you read the text messages,
it just equals out to somebody's just on an average day.
I mean,
if you look at most of the text messages,
They're basically a guy who's talking to a girl and trying to set something up for his birthday.
Take,
for instance,
he's asking this girl,
what are you going to do?
Are you going to come to my birthday party?
So 15 minutes before the husband leaves,
he's having a text conversation with a young lady.
He's not looking to see if neighbors are home,
or he's not canvassing the place,
or he's not in the car with someone else while they're driving around looking through a neighborhood.
He's texting back and forth about a birthday party.
So I find that very unusual.
And then at 11.29,
a minute before the husband is supposed to leave,
he texts her,
well,
you might not want to watch,
because a lot of girls know me in there.
You know,
this is one of the places he's probably frequents,
right?
She replies back,
well,
that's fine.
I like girls too.
Even afterwards,
if I go to some of the text messages,
Around 1234,
1234,
he's supposed to be gone with the wind in a car somewhere,
leaving the scene.
He's texting,
you flaw girl.
And then at
101, it's what you doing?
If I was to tie someone up,
stab them,
and push them in the tub,
there's no way in the world that I'd be texting,
what you doing?
Or you flaw.
I would be...
be scared out of my mind.
So reading through these text messages,
there's nothing in this phone after someone's supposed to commit a crime that harsh,
that heinous,
that would tell you that they did it.
I don't see it.
Usually people in that situation become very agitated very quickly.
So we might expect them to look pretty chaotic,
to look pretty distressed.
Oftentimes,
they actually will be
blab it out to somebody that they committed the homicide and that's oftentimes how they're caught in this case deontay did none of that um so in fact he seemed to kind of go back to normal and there's really kind of two ways of reading that one is that he didn't commit the homicide you know so he's not feeling agitated he's not experiencing that because he's innocent the
other possibility is that he's a psychopath and so he doesn't experience uh those sorts of emotional roller coasters that people normally do if they've committed a homicide
You know,
I've seen other murders done the same thing and committed homicides
I didn't go right off and try to find the girlfriend and have a night with them and that's something most of this would it wouldn't think to do but again it's hard to know I mean we don't know that he did it you know so it's hard to you know obviously I can't say he's a psychopath and this behavior indicates that he's guilty of
this homicide I can only try to put it in perspective of here's how to understand that behavior if he committed the homicide and here's how we can understand that behavior if he did not commit the homicide
We just got in the Excel spreadsheets for all the calls.
So we do have what was requested.
Oh,
good.
But as I was going through,
more or less reading out the outgoing text messages between,
let's say,
1115 and 1230,
there were some in these records that he did not have.
Right on the list so I don't understand why that is but obviously the more text messages we have right he had better messages around the time that I didn't have and I was like whoa that's that's very interesting right in this one there's there's not around
like 11 30 and stuff like that
I don't have any but you have yeah there's 11 29
11 31 uh 11 48
1152,
1158,
two of those,
three of those.
Wow.
1203,
1209.
Now here,
this is a little bit of a gap.
1209,
then the next one is 1222.
See now,
I have,
yeah,
I have one at 1227,
and it picks back up at 1 o'clock.
You have a 1227 outgoing?
Yeah.
Really?
That's so weird.
So you have some that are not on here.
Right.
Yes.
This is insane.
Right.
I mean,
the good part is,
is we seem to have a lot of text activity from him during that time frame,
which is very helpful to us.
Because I don't know how you could be involved in such a,
like,
a gruesome,
torturous type of killing like this.
And then you're texting this lighthearted text about...
Are you going to come to the party with me?
And are you going to be intimidated if the other strippers are there?
And she's like,
no,
you know,
I don't care about the strippers.
I used to be a stripper,
so it's fine with me.
Okay,
cool.
Why you...
Who does that?
Yeah,
or even while you're...
you know if there's multiple people and your role is to you know grab the cash and the the jewelry and something while she's maybe screaming on the floor or something i mean it's yeah it's impossible so i think that's good i
don't understand why the records his records show but i don't know how i mean these are the actual phone records so
But why take out the text from the time that around the murder would have happened?
That's so weird.
Because they want a blank.
They want a blank.
See,
there was nothing going on.
If they actually did that,
that's very important.
Yeah,
we'll have to see where those came from.
I don't know.
Do we really know if they've been through all of these records and have analyzed them as extensively as we have?
Because they might not have.
It seems that they just ended everything after Dante got the DNA hit.
I mean,
we haven't seen any other reports.
I haven't seen any of the reports that they've analyzed anything.
So they may not even know this even exists.
So we're looking at times between,
let's just figure 1130 when the husband leaves the house and 1228 when he's pinging off of the tower seven miles away,
eight miles away.
1130 and 1228.
57 calls.
57,
okay.
So it's almost a text a minute.
So how do we explain that there's only five
SMS messages on the extraction and they're relying on the extraction with a very minimal activity implying that he was up and available for an hour to commit this murder?
But if there are 57 text messages on the call detail records,
it's almost,
and it's showing,
it's almost one a minute.
I'd have to go with the confidence in the T-Mobile data.
Over the extraction?
Well.
Both,
but I mean the cold detail records are accurate.
I mean my opinion I've analyzed thousands of them,
multiple different companies and we have a very high confidence in the cellular network and then computerized systems that they use to capture and document calls and texts in some cases data sessions.
So the phone extraction thing is a
For me,
it's a mixed bag,
as you see.
Why didn't it capture on the device that call that the network captured?
He deleted a lot of texts,
too.
He deleted a lot of stuff.
So if he deleted those text messages during the time frame,
they're not going to come up with the extraction then,
right?
That's what I'm thinking.
I can't find them separately in a deleted file.
Right.
But that's the kind of...
How I would approach it if I was going to drill down on this and try to mesh it and flush out more activity during the time frame necessary.
Well,
you know,
to some degree we've been limited in what we can do because we don't have the ability to do in-person depositions.
We haven't had the ability to meet with our client.
And then with,
you know,
if you schedule a phone,
we know that,
I mean,
they're not supposed to record the conversations and I'm not saying that they're doing it.
It's just that they have the ability,
let's put it this way,
they have the ability to record the conversations without you knowing,
but I'm not,
I'm not saying they're doing that,
but.
We just held off until we can have like the old-fashioned visits where you actually go to the jail and you're in a private room with the client and you know nobody's recording you.
It's hell,
it's hell.
Everybody,
you know,
went through like a mental stress or whatever because you have the pandemic raising havoc.
And then you got the whole court system being down.
And then nobody knowing when they're going to go to trial.
Like the dates of the court opening up,
nobody really knows or whatever.
And treatment-wise,
being in jail is not the best.
And it's always been like that.
So like.
They're making up their own rules to aim towards me that I have to follow and then if I don't follow them,
I'm penalized.
You know they have restricted visitation where I can't get visitation,
but sometimes it'll just let it go through.
I don't know if they took it off where I can get it now,
but they restricted my visitation where I couldn't get it.
They try to isolate him and make him feel alone and make him feel there's nobody out here.
that's warning them anytime you try to call them you try to have a little small conversation with them anything you say they say oh you said the wrong word now uh my wife's number's blocked i got a friend on this block my number's blocked and if i ain't call us he can't get through now so
the only time we could reach him is through a letter and i think he tried to write us a couple times and they just didn't send
Because we get word through a third party,
well,
like,
hey,
did you get the letter?
No,
we didn't get any letter.
It started to weigh on him for a while.
It could take a toll on anyone.
They're trying to keep them separate as much as possible.
They've taken away certain liberties that they have in the jail to limit contact with other inmates.
And a lot of inmates are suffering because they're on lockdown in a jail cell by themselves without contact with other people.
So mentally,
a lot of our clients are suffering,
not just...
physically,
including Deonte.
He really wants this case to go forward and go to trial,
but without a future court date,
he's just kind of feeling,
you know,
restless and desperate to go to court and worried and anxious.
It's difficult because he's been in...
In the jail for so long,
and he was now just reaching the end.
And now we have to tell him that it's on hold indefinitely without a future date.
It is.
A doctor came.
A doctor comes to clear you,
to make sure you're no longer suicidal.
And all it takes is you telling them.
oh you know i never was because you want to get off because it's basically taking you from one torture placing you into another one that's more so greater where you have to wrestle with these thoughts with the pills it was just like a whole episode of just like wanting to give up just being done with everything because dude just being tired man
i don't really like thinking about it because it placed myself in the dark spot but
If you just call it quit,
everything could be over with.
You won't have those problems anymore.
You won't have to deal with all that.
And I'm really dying to know when I'm going to trial,
when trial's coming up.
But I guess I'll speak with my lawyers when they come and see me.
Or I'll figure out that way,
because I'm jealous,
jealous.
I'm over jail now.
I'm tired of jail.
Jail is too much.
Hey there.
I haven't seen you in a while.
You never call.
Who?
There's your hand.
It's red.
Judge,
and I can let you know that we reached out to the lab to do some additional testing.
So
I'm anticipating hearing from the lab any day now.
What's the issue with the DNA?
There's some new...
Techniques that have come about since this test was done.
So you're suggesting that the science has advanced and they have new techniques that they've developed and can answer more questions.
Yes,
with the new developments in the testing,
they're able to go in and test it and make matches and develop full profiles that they couldn't even a year ago and now they can.
We at least learned that what they're doing with respect to having
Retesting things and some things that have never been tested and then retesting other things that have been done.
And then when I talked to
Sherry out in the hall,
she was like,
well,
we'll see how it pans up.
You know,
it could we don't know how it'll you know,
like it could go either way in terms of what the results.
I mean,
anytime you start testing something,
you never know what you're going to get.
All of the DNA was rerun,
and it confirmed that the first run was correct.
The defendant's DNA was on the knife,
on the Kershaw knife outside the home.
The defendant's DNA was on the looped belt that was used to tie Mrs.
Su.
But also on the door from the point of entry,
the DNA wasn't sufficient to be able to compare to anyone with the technology that was available at the time.
And now that DNA profile that was previously there,
but
Not enough to compare was enough to compare,
and it was a single source to the defendant.
It doesn't look good,
right?
Someone's DNA being on the exterior of a door where a person was murdered is not,
you know,
very positive for the defendant,
and it's not ambiguous like some of the mixtures that we have in this case.
So the who question has been answered for that sample,
essentially,
and...
So then it really just becomes a question of how did that DNA get there and when did that DNA get there and DNA doesn't ever tell us those things.
Is it because he participated in this crime or is it because it transferred here through some other process?
A person's DNA being on an item doesn't mean they touched an item,
doesn't mean they handled an item.
And just the DNA itself would never be enough.
But in addition to that,
now there is an unidentified area of DNA.
a Gatorade bottle that was found inside the home.
You know,
it just stood out of place.
Like,
it was in this room that was like a spare room.
It was very clean,
and nobody in the house drank that.
So we do have a piece of evidence that they collected they think could be the perpetrator,
and turns out it was a Gatorade bottle.
Yes,
they got a DNA off it,
but they can't match it to anybody.
They can't match it to the family.
It doesn't match to our client.
So there was an aspect of the testing that actually helps us.
And then there were prints lifted off of the jewelry boxes that were opened,
and it was obvious that,
you know...
Somebody was going through them,
unless it was all staged,
but it looked like that arguably was a person who potentially was robbing the place,
and none of those prints came back to our client.
And so they're deemed to be unidentified.
So that,
you know,
that of course is significant.
But we have not been given this fingerprint information,
which is a shame considering how many years later.
I think the first thing I noticed,
I heard like a screeching,
squeaky screeching sound and my dog started barking.
Around like how long did you hear this squeaky screeching?
Seconds.
So what happened when you went over to the door?
The blinds were closed,
so I lifted a blind.
Okay.
So you were looking through a blind through your glass door?
Correct.
And where were you looking?
Directly.
across the street,
out front,
directly in the front yard,
which was across the street at the Suze house.
Did you notice any cars there?
I don't remember there being,
certainly there wasn't any car parked in front of my door or their door.
Now the driveways are wide,
so maybe,
you know,
I think,
I don't even remember if my car was parked in the driveway,
but nothing in front of our doors.
All right,
so what did you see?
I don't know whether it was someone from the inside pulling.
I thought maybe it was a dog or something that somebody was trying to pull inside.
My thought process when all this screeching and everything,
I mean,
you just don't think.
That it's at noon,
something horrible.
And I thought it was a dog.
Maybe they had an older dog.
I thought maybe the dog had been hit by a car.
The dog was deaf.
You know,
I didn't know.
And I thought,
well,
maybe
Jill was trying to get the dog in the house.
I didn't know what,
I don't know what.
Now,
how long were you standing by that door looking across the street?
10 or 15 seconds,
maybe.
Not long.
I stayed there until the door closed.
Okay.
So you saw the door close?
Yes.
That's it,
one,
three,
two,
seven,
yeah,
that's it.
This whole thing had her very upset.
Oh,
I totally agree.
I understand.
You didn't help her into that.
I'm sorry.
I apologize,
but there's not much I can do about that.
I apologize.
Well,
there is.
I'm right in the building where the lawyers are.
Okay.
No,
no,
what I'm just saying is I apologize for upsetting her,
but there's not much I could do.
I stopped and knocked on the door.
I don't know who her lawyers are or anything.
It's not her lawyers.
You don't have lawyers.
I'm a lawyer,
but I'm in the same building as the people who represented this kid.
Okay.
They're on the sixth floor,
Mike,
whatever his name is.
Yeah,
Orlando.
I'm on the fifth floor.
Right.
I'm right there.
OK.
All right.
So you can call my office,
and she'll be happy to talk to you.
OK.
Basically,
I came back because I wanted to see exactly what we could see and a couple other things that had questions.
That's it.
That's what you can see.
Yeah.
Nothing's changed,
right?
I mean,
nothing's changed there.
Did you see the dogs?
Yeah.
That's what prompted this whole thing.
Right.
The doors were the same.
She was in the kitchen.
The blinds are the same,
too?
Blinds are the same.
She heard the dogs were going crazy.
Right.
two or three times she said,
get away from there,
get away from there.
Finally she came to get them,
she looked out and saw the tail end of whatever was going on.
Whatever the door was going on.
So whatever she described,
that's the perspective.
Okay,
alright.
And you don't have cameras,
right?
You didn't have cameras back then?
Uh,
no.
Alright,
we're scared.
I was scheduled for trial at the end of the year and,
you know,
I got some problems with this case.
Well,
there's some problems with the case.
I mean,
you also have a guilty client,
but there are some problems with the case.
Well,
yeah.
Clearly,
somebody alive in that house around noon opened the door for some reason which we don't know.
And we know that Nanyo was at his office during that time.
We know that he left.
His house sometime around 1130 and with the evidence now showing that somebody opened the door,
clearly it was either Jill that opened the door,
maybe prior to being murdered,
or it was the suspect who opened the door,
maybe trying to either flee or to look out front to see if anybody's coming.
So this clearly helps Nanyo in his case as an alibi,
even though there's so many discrepancies.
And things that he said that don't really,
that aren't really accurate.
So,
you know,
looking back on this,
this is pivotal at this point.
And Betty's clearly a very important witness in this case.
Check the garage,
man.
I was there.
You don't need to check the fucking garage.
Why not?
Because you said you're in the library.
So?
What's wrong with that?
So what if you're not in the library?
Then where were you?
In my car.
What were you doing in your car?
Sleeping.
So I'm gonna ask you the same question again.
So you don't fuck this up.
Be honest with me.
Did you stay in your car sleeping or did you go to the library?
I say that,
okay,
I'm sorry,
I said that too.
You fucking lied about that too.
Because I don't want to seem like an asshole.
No,
because you know I'm gonna fucking find out the truth.
Oh,
that's him.
Let me make sure.
One second.
Hey,
Mike,
do you have a copy,
a photocopy of Justin's car in the file anywhere?
OK,
yeah,
that's what I wanted to see.
I kind of wanted to compare.
All right,
thanks.
It may,
but I'm not sold.
not a hundred percent um it could just be the angle of the car that that's that what it could that's what it could be but hold on
And boom,
and there we are.
This is him big screen.
You can see the Ford.
You can actually see the white T-shirt inside with the Breaking Bad on it.
And he exits at 12.20.
He's leaving now.
I'm trying to simulate the actual drive from Broward College to the crime scene.
I'm going as fast as I can without breaking any rules or traffic rules.
We're going to see how fast we can get there from the school.
It took me 10 minutes.
So I guess what I'm saying is,
given that,
I guess we...
Both of the statements of them are problematic.
Yes.
But what I'm saying is they're going to fall back on the video surveillance to prove that it couldn't have been,
for example,
couldn't have been the sun because of the video surveillance.
I'm just saying whatever else needs to be done on that end to investigate,
to see,
you know...
In other words,
I...
We don't want to spin our wheels with trying to make it seem like the son was involved.
Right.
If they're going to be able to come back and show proof,
conclusive proof,
that he was never alone in the house with his mother.
Right,
right.
Zach,
basketball got covered.
Mark this.
It's half full.
You gotta go get it,
all right?
I'll be fine.
I'm a finder of fact.
You know,
I'm going to review the evidence and the discovery that's given to us,
and I'm going to find the things that are good for Deonte and find the things that are bad for Deonte and present them to the defense.
You know,
the lawyers are the ones who then have to take that information and construct it into a case as what they feel is the best logical defense.
Tag,
tag,
tag!
You know,
before with the knife being outside a front-lock door,
you know,
there's all kinds of speculation as to how that got there.
But with the stuff being on the entrance to the glass,
that's pretty incriminating evidence that puts him at that back door at least touching it at some point.
And what is your opinion personally?
Personally?
I,
that's tough to say.
I mean,
looking at it now,
my gut feeling going into the trial is that the defense trying to show that it's someone else is going to be difficult to prove.
Even though they don't have to prove it,
they have to prove it.
And they need to prove it in front of the jury.
And that's going to be difficult for them to do.
So what is going to be your strategy for the trial?
Well,
I mean,
I think the thrust of the argument is that the person that,
the perpetrator was familiar with the house and had been there before,
you know,
targeting Justin's room and then the master bedroom,
taking down the cameras,
because we don't think it's really a coincidence.
that this happened after these parties.
You know,
it seems more likely that a perpetrator is somebody that could have known Justin,
could have been there before.
you know,
and go,
sort of go down that path.
When I first got involved,
there was a lot of talk in the,
like,
Justin did it or Nanyo did it.
But if you start out on that tone and then the jury feel bad for the person,
they're gonna look at you like,
you know,
okay,
their defense is that he did it and they're gonna be like,
there's no way.
So that's why,
you know,
in the end,
it wouldn't be a wise angle.
And that's...
not our role to solve the crime,
so to speak.
So you just try to sort of throw out as much stuff as you can to create reasonable doubt.
One of you,
this is the process of selecting a juror.
I am going to ask you a series of questions that are related to whether you can serve as a juror in this case,
okay?
Under
Florida law,
in order for a juror to even sit on a case in which the death penalty is an option,
they have to be able to consider the death penalty.
You don't want people who have...
streams so both disqualify you if you would never consider the death penalty you're disqualified if you will always consider the death penalty appropriate for murder in the first degree you're disqualified are you able to sit and listen to everything ms schneider and i put on anything the defense may put on and
consider life in prison okay any alternative are you able to consider and really consider imposing the death penalty you're talking to people that
woke up that morning and just said,
oh,
okay,
I think I have jury duty today,
and then flash forward to six hours later,
and they're sitting in a room with a judge and a defendant with four defense attorneys and two prosecutors.
Tell me all of your thoughts on arguably the heaviest topic that you could discuss with somebody.
I mean,
and you're trying to take that little glimmer of information and figure out how it's gonna shape the rest of the case.
That's why I try to delve as deep as I possibly can in the limited...
Framework that we're given to try to identify those people who doesn't matter what we present,
they're going to kill Deontay.
We give them numbers.
One could never impose death.
Seven will always impose death.
So we don't want any sixes.
We don't want any fives.
We want mostly twos,
maybe some threes.
But what really ends up happening is kind of in the middle end up there.
And then,
of course,
the state,
they'll come up with.
All these lame excuses to strike all the black jurors,
which of course we fight.
Let's face it,
they're probably going to be looking for white women that have some money.
Only 3%
of counties across the country still regularly impose death sentences.
Broward County is one of those counties.
Yeah,
we had six,
I believe six executions last year.
That's a lot of people to kill.
Like a one person every two months.
Basically what it boils down to during a pandemic.
I think we're happy with the jury that we have,
but we won't know if it's a good jury until the trial's over.
The prosecution sent a great message when she said,
you're never truly going to know because unless you saw it,
you wouldn't know.
And if you saw it,
would you be a witness?
You wouldn't be a juror.
They don't seem to want me,
but they won't admit.
I must be some kind of creature if they haven't been.
Having a hard time in this crazy town.
Having a hard time.
There's no love to be found.
Opening statements are now underway after a gruesome murder back in 2014.
Today,
a man suspected of killing a woman and then making a daring escape from court is back in front of a judge.
This time for a jury to determine his fate.
On trial is 27 year old...
Deontay Reziles,
the man accused of killing Sue seven years ago.
The
59-year-old was found stabbed and bound in the bathtub of her Davey home in September of 2014.
Reziles pleaded not guilty to first-degree murder.
Prosecutor Maria Snyder,
in her opening argument,
told the jury Reziles'
DNA was found on a belt used to restrict Mrs.
Sue.
His lawyer says Reziles didn't kill Mrs.
Sue that it was someone her son invited to a home.
during a party so this morning the judge told members of the jury that he expects this trial to last the rest of the month and it could even last through the first week of december that is the very latest live in fort lauderdale this morning cyra onward local 10 news they
would call justin sue mr sue approach the witness box and when you arrive please remain standing.
It's definitely something with the human brain,
blocks out that,
because
I saw Brainy,
but I remember looking at her face,
lifeless,
one eye open,
one eye closed.
You know,
when you find mommy dead in the bathtub,
you're not a grown man.
You're the little boy,
and she's using that emotional connection.
And he appears to be somewhat aware of the impact of his words because he knows the stronger his memory is,
the more clear it is to the jury that,
no,
he's not the one who did this.
No one should be accused of killing their own mother for hours in a completely naked...
In a spray paint suit with still my mother's blood on my skin,
I can still smell it all the time.
It was horrible.
You know,
having to strip and be searched and,
like,
being treated as a suspect,
as I guess you should be,
because that's,
like,
the,
you know,
typically the crime is always,
like,
the first,
you know,
it's always,
like,
the husband or the kid,
right?
It's always the people sort of in there.
So I get that part of it,
but it was sad because I can't,
I was empathizing,
really,
with,
like,
what the hell was this kid going through in this exact moment?
To me,
it was heartbreaking.
And,
um...
It was one of the times that I actually,
I think I had a couple of tears because
I can't even imagine someone coming home and finding their parent.
in that condition,
so I think he went through so much.
I don't doubt his emotions,
but they had lived there for all those years and there'd never been a burglary,
and then all of a sudden,
this one time where he's on his own,
you know,
he sort of goes wild and has all these parties and bringing people into the house.
It's not just a coincidence.
You alerted the guests to the fact that there were cameras in the house,
correct?
Yes.
Were you aware of some of these people that you had over to your house that were sketchy and drugged up all the time?
No.
Didn't you have a friend that got swooped up in some type of a DEA bus?
If you recall my memory,
maybe.
I can't remember.
I wasn't the only one.
I think a couple of us entertained the idea that it could have been one of
Justin's friends or that might have had access to the home.
I mean,
that's like good theory,
right?
Like,
I'm with that,
right?
Someone that knows that Justin had knives,
Someone who's maybe been to the house.
I'm okay with that theory,
but it fell maybe slightly flat in the sense that they didn't pursue it any deeper than just kind of throwing it out there.
Much of today really focused on the testimony of the victim's son.
That son having to tell the jurors about that day.
He is the one who found his mother.
Justin said in court today that this was just something that no child should ever have to experience,
finding his mother in that bathtub.
It was really emotional and very heavy in court.
He asked if it was a white male or a black male.
You didn't have any trouble understanding the question,
right?
No.
And your only response was that it looked like two.
Yes,
but the only trouble there is that I could not tell one or another.
But I was obligated,
she was one or two.
And I tried to do my best to give the information.
And since you originally thought that it was your son and your son's skin is white.
That's right.
Even though it was a black and white camera,
you can't mistaken me for a white person on a black and white camera.
Because white is white.
It's going to come out white.
You know,
my color skin,
if anything,
is going to come out gray.
Like you said,
they kept on pressuring me and pressuring me to give them,
was it black,
was it white?
And just said,
looks white to me.
I don't think anybody really made a big deal about that testimony,
to be honest with you.
That is testimony.
That is evidence.
Nanyau is giving us evidence and saying that at the time,
he looked white to me.
And that's in his interrogation.
So that is evidence.
We can't decide not to listen to it because he said it.
It was written.
It was closest to the moment that he saw it in the video.
There was one thing when he said about the cameras that were disconnected that he went to work
I kind of thought that maybe at first what a coincidence that he goes to work logs onto the computer and at that time someone is messing with the cameras or they unplugged it it was like it's weird yeah it's very weird it's weird and
that but that was it right it was it's weird no further
examining of that,
right?
I definitely believe that they did not pursue the untruths with Justin or the father enough.
But this young man and this husband lost a wife and a mother.
So
I, as the defense,
am going to get up there and badger them.
How is that going to appear to the jury?
What's the perception of that to the jury?
I understand why they didn't do it.
Does it make it right?
Not necessarily.
But
I understand why they didn't.
We want the video to exist because on the video,
he's saying it was a white male.
That's very...
That's like one of the biggest pieces of evidence in his favor.
Plus,
he's saying he thinks there's a relationship to his son,
and his son is white.
I'm going to take issue with whether Nanyao said he saw a person who was white.
They asked him,
was he black,
was he white,
after he said he didn't see anything of the person because they had their face covered.
And he said,
looked white to me.
And I don't know that that's a conclusive,
concrete answer.
I think that Nanyao was surmising what it was.
but
that doesn't exonerate the defendant and it doesn't in any way shape or form explain why his dna is there you know the dna evidence that basically is the evidence against the client so we're
challenging the program that they used to come to their conclusions in this second round of testing in
2020.
One of the problems with the StarMix software is it's taking any small change in the analytical process and treating it with massive implication.
Therefore,
when you hear a statistic you can't know whether if that sample was run again.
In this laboratory or a different laboratory,
whether it be within the same ballpark.
So in terms of the statistic,
I don't have any confidence in the reliability.
In other words,
I don't know that if we ran this again,
we would get a completely different result.
And let me make clear,
the result could go higher as well as lower.
It was really more about like testing methodology.
And it was like...
beyond kind of the scope of the jury in a way.
You know,
they were talking about one one billionth of a parcel and one one trillionth and taking a DNA sample.
All the doubt that was brought up relating back to the lab was like technical jargon.
And now how,
um,
does DNA transfer something that can easily happen or is it impossible?
I think the fact we've got so many masks on tells us how easy DNA is transferred.
The more research we do,
the more difficult interpretation becomes in terms of how DNA got onto something.
In my view,
it simply has to be DNA evidence and transfer simply has to be consolidated with the other evidence in the case.
It doesn't,
the scientists should not be saying it definitely got there by touch,
it definitely got there that day or whenever without other information.
So the science alone can only tell you so much and then it should be matched up.
In Scotland we call it corroboration,
where the pieces of evidence must all point towards a consistent story.
The science is just part of that.
He said,
very clearly,
he said,
DNA must support other evidence.
And for us,
for some of us,
that was very important because we felt,
OK,
there is DNA.
I think right now
You're sitting in that chair.
If I move that chair to some other person's house,
were you in the house?
No,
that DNA was in the house.
So when you look at just the DNA,
I said,
is that enough?
Yeah,
you're right.
Maybe one DNA.
But again,
we're seeing this kind of interesting line.
Back door,
front door,
in the house.
One,
fine.
And that came up during deliberation.
It was like.
DNA is not enough.
And it was like,
but how much DNA?
Good morning.
Good morning again.
So,
the smudge from the door,
single source,
correct?
Yes.
You have absolutely no issue with that.
No.
You have no issue with either the wet science,
the development of the DNA itself.
Yeah.
Or with the statistic.
I prefer the random match probability of Africa.
It's going to be in the building.
All right,
so you like another way of doing it better,
but you're not saying that that single source from the door is incorrect and it's not the defendant.
That's correct.
And you are not telling these ladies and gentlemen of the jury that he is not included in the other two samples.
You're just having an issue with the numbers.
That's correct.
Thank you.
Nothing further.
The defendant,
DNA.
Was there.
And just like I said,
why my DNA is not there?
You know why my DNA is not there?
Because I wasn't there.
Plain and simple,
I wasn't there.
I had previously collected a partially empty
Gatorade bottle from the guest bedroom.
The residence was in immaculate condition except for the areas that I previously discussed about disturbance and ransacking.
And this guest bedroom was in immaculate condition as well,
and this Gatorade bottle just looked out of place.
The crime scene people in the state attorney's office at the time,
they made a big deal about it,
believing that that had to somehow be related to
The perpetrator,
so we do have unidentified DNA on that.
So they had to concede that.
So there was DNA not matching the defendant,
matching male.
So male,
but not the defendant.
And then prints.
And did you examine the prints from the jewelry boxes in the master bedroom?
Yes,
sir.
All right,
and you didn't identify any of those prints to Mr.
Gonzalez,
did you?
No.
They had fingerprints that were on the jewelry box that were unexplained.
But the people that you brought in that were at the party,
you never fingerprinted them.
You only swabbed them.
Like,
if you had unexplained fingerprints in the house and you're trying to define who fingerprints they are,
you would want to fingerprint anybody that was possibly in that house so that...
You can say,
hey,
I have fingerprints of someone in the house,
and this is their fingerprints,
you know?
But I think that because the prosecution was so bent on,
this is our guy,
we must focus everything on him,
if we make any other,
you know.
Doubts that would be creating doubt.
The people who were into the house,
none of the reports show that profiles were ever developed on any of the swabs.
So,
you know,
so yeah,
she's bringing out that swabs were taken,
but it doesn't list them.
In any of the reports as having been,
having had a DNA profile developed and then compared to anything.
...and make such judgment.
I'm Mr.
Alex Guion.
Yes,
yes,
uh,
great.
Could you raise your right hand for me?
Approximately how many different people did he ask you to provide letters to trying to get somebody to get him a cell phone to use in the gym?
A few people,
but the only person that
I was in contact with was Crystal.
Crystal
Isaacs? Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Did you ever receive anything of value for helping the defendant now?
I was always compensated with money.
Okay.
Did he provide you that money directly,
or did he have someone give it to you?
No,
he had Crystal give it to me.
I know they kept calling my name,
and it made me very upset.
Because I wasn't able to speak,
I had to just sit there and...
This heart is dirty.
But actually,
I'm glad I came to face that.
I needed to face it.
It's a part of my healing.
It took a lot out of me to come back here.
What made you come anyway?
Deontay,
his support.
I kept thinking about him and I think,
you know,
I thought it would be,
it would make him feel better.
Whether I come back or not,
I think Deontay knows that
I'm with him in spirit.
Would you say you still love him?
Of course.
I love him.
Please stay in your full name for the break.
Jason Hendry.
Scoggy Lasting for work.
G-N-B-R-I-C-K.
Alright,
so we're talking about,
the first call we're talking about is call 129.
Have you had an opportunity to review the CD that I have of the call?
I have.
Yeah,
we'd like to publish this.
We may.
I'm going to be there for,
I'm going to be there for a while.
When is this going to be?
The bribes,
you know,
trying to create so many alibis and whatever.
To me,
someone that's innocent doesn't do that.
You would waste your energy perhaps proving your innocence,
not trying to create all these stories.
At no point in time on any of those calls did he ever say he was at that home.
that he ever said that anything of the nature of,
oh,
this is what happened,
I need to cover up this that happened.
Yeah,
those phone calls were questionable.
Him trying to get people to lie.
Why?
I don't know.
But that wasn't what was on trial.
How do you give an inmate a phone?
That's my whole two things.
They trying to frame him.
Seriously,
that ain't got nothing.
That charge that y'all got,
that ain't got nothing to do with this murder case.
They shouldn't be able to use that,
man.
I have so many questions.
He had a hundred cases on him.
He had a hundred cases.
He ain't say nothing about killing that lady on none of them phone calls.
That's some straight bullshit.
They know it.
Why is this even here right now?
Why did the judge even allow her to continue with that?
Why were they allowed to give him a phone and set him up and then listen to all his phone calls?
Why is that allowed?
Why is that okay?
I think they're definitely trying to confuse the jury.
I have no faith in this system here.
None at all.
And I feel like it's a complete setup.
Some places,
Sam,
I'm not.
I'm gonna get out the car.
You're gonna have to feel from the backseat.
Not necessarily because you in danger,
because I ain't gonna let nobody harm you.
Anybody with me,
I'm gonna protect them.
But because a lot of people gonna run because they thank you,
the police.
You know how some white people,
they see black folks,
and they grab their purse?
Well,
see,
it's the opposite.
Who you think did it?
That's on camera?
You damn right.
Say what you gotta say.
Say it.
He on Moochie's side.
Who did it?
I know him.
I don't really know his name,
but her son.
Okay.
All right then.
Thank you.
Her son and her girl.
Shit if a bit no evidence knowledge like I said,
I know
Bro,
shit,
I'm from Paul,
wait,
from Westside.
Okay,
man.
Man,
come on,
man.
All that shit,
evidence,
everything led back to her son,
man.
That's for Moochie.
Moochie.
I don't know if you remember the boy that escaped from Broward County Courthouse.
I love dog.
What is with him?
You ain't see the other side?
Hello,
mama.
Excuse me,
baby.
Oh,
you got one?
Thank you.
I ain't see my dirty so long.
We're trying to get behind that boy because they're trying to get him to death penalty.
It's this against you,
child.
They trying.
If you look into the story,
I believe that you'll kind of believe it's us that he's innocent.
And he needs the people's support or they're going to give him the death penalty.
Let's get that in the Bible.
Guess what?
In America,
we are slaves in America.
Let's get that from the Bible.
Leviticus 26 verse 17.
In America,
a dead black dog is worth more than a living breathing black man.
Many black men are accused of murder.
If the brother committed that crime,
he committed it.
I hear him.
See,
that's why I want to walk off because you see that?
You don't know Moochie.
You sitting out there talking about God,
but you judging somebody.
That's why I don't want to go over there because I've been there cussing his ass out.
That's why nobody don't listen to them.
You come fucking yelling at people.
You're not doing God's work yelling.
God don't yell.
Y'all false prophets going to hell.
Bitch.
There we go.
Thank you.
And why you getting no pass on something for me?
Please,
so he don't get this death penalty.
I'll pass my itch work when I pass my itch.
There we go.
Thank you.
Hold on.
We filming.
One time for me.
Let me let the winner.
Wait,
come on,
Sam,
catch him.
Get up.
We filming.
Now say,
justice for Moochie.
Hey!
Thank you.
Who is that?
There's somebody behind us.
Woo!
There's somebody behind us!
Sir,
are you going to walk into our witness box and when you arrive,
please remain standing until you get sworn in?
Thank you,
sir.
Good afternoon,
Mr.
Baragloth.
This is our witness stand over here.
Come on up.
Alright,
I want to direct your attention to the phone activity.
This particular day between 1129 and 1227 PM,
seven incoming text messages,
not a single response.
Correct.
Okay.
At 1227,
what did you discover on the phone?
At 1227 on September 8th,
there was an outgoing message to a Chanel Campbell with the abbreviation
WYA.
Do you know what the abbreviation
WYA means?
Where are you at?
During the crime,
this is a person who texts religiously all day long.
And in the meantime,
it's not because there's just too many coincidences where he did not text at all.
But then after when he finally texts,
I forgot what the time,
I think it was like 1247 or something like that.
The time where he texts someone and says,
where are you at?
Awesome.
outgoing i don't know what they're talking about now i'm really wondering what records you have because i've never seen any of that this is exactly what we received from the state so we are objecting i don't know what they're talking about outgoing i i i can't see here yeah
i can see where it says outgoing but i can't see from where i don't know how to read these relax i've just been accused of presenting false testimony i mean i take that a little personally Absolutely.
Listen.
to get upset.
Just relax.
Don't be calling attorneys honey and things like that.
It just doesn't fly,
all right?
You've been practicing too long for that.
Let's do this.
Counsel,
you reduce whatever you want to writing,
and the state can take a look at it,
and they can respond to it at their leisure,
all right?
See everybody back tomorrow at 9 o'clock.
So we have a witness that's gonna testify about what's in those T-Mobile records,
the calls during that 11.30 to 12.30.
Can you describe what outgoing messages you found from 1130 to 1230?
You want me to tell you each one?
Yes.
Just for the time being.
1136 outgoing,
there are two of them.
1147,
1152,
1158,
1202.
12.09 p.m.
12.22 p.m.
12.26 p.m.
That's it till 12.30 p.m.
sir.
All right,
thank you.
Go ahead,
counsel.
Sir,
where on the records that you received,
the quality of the records,
does it say what time zone the records are in?
The records themselves,
which is quite unusual.
when I received these because this is not a standard production from T-Mobile.
So therefore what your office provided me were records that I had to take and basically try to figure out how using how T-Mobile operates what time zone they were in.
But the bottom line is that that's your opinion.
You didn't get that information from T-Mobile did you?
No,
ma'am.
Sure didn't.
Okay.
In fact,
if you Google what time zone are T-Mobile records provided in,
it says on the T-Mobile supports website that it is Pacific time,
doesn't it?
No,
ma'am.
It doesn't?
I don't know where you got that from.
I've been in this business since two...
I don't care.
You can Google anything,
okay?
But I'm going to tell you that if you really wanted to know what that time zone was and we could stop all this bantering back and forth,
your guys should have pulled the T-Mobile key.
Okay,
so...
Bye!
You can't really testify with absolute accuracy that those records that you're reading are even T-Mobile records.
Do you realize what you're saying?
You're the ones that gave them to us.
You're the ones that asserted that these were true and accurate records from your office,
and now you're contradicting your own records?
I'm so happy that you think this is funny,
but maybe you could just answer my question.
It's actually ridiculous that you would even go down this path.
Okay.
Will you answer my question,
sir?
That extraction that was done by the police,
when did you receive that?
Okay,
extraction,
what kind?
Are you talking about the Celebrant report?
Correct.
Isn't that called a phone extraction?
You tell me,
you're the expert.
listen uh mr slavinski is getting out of hand you just respond to the questions all right i don't want you arguing with council council i don't want you arguing with the witness you ask the questions you answer them that's it mr slavinski understood i understand you thank you
It is intrusive that in the extraction,
the phone calls that take place from 11.27 to 12.30,
that exact sequence of calls appears in the call detail records that you received three hours early.
I can't comment on that.
Okay.
They were trying to show that the defendant was answering phone calls during the hour of this homicide.
And then in the middle of trial,
they realized that there was a discrepancy between the time zone,
between the T-Mobile records and the extraction,
because the extraction is in real time.
If you're here,
like I'm here in Florida,
right?
The time here in Florida is on my phone.
So when you extract my phone,
you're going to get the time here because that's what...
My phone has.
T-Mobile is on the West Coast.
T-Mobile provides records on West Coast standard time.
So the discrepancy is because the records are three hours behind.
The Davie Police Department,
when they obtain these records,
they're supposed to get like a cover page that defines
you know,
whose records these are and would probably give information about how to read them and the time and that.
Well,
they never got though,
they never obtained that initial page or pages.
So everybody believed,
because there was no reason to believe otherwise,
that they were Eastern Standard Time.
This witness says it looks something like it,
but it's not the normal format,
doesn't appear to be the normal format that he would get it.
The versions to say it's not not coming in.
That was hard.
It was certainly a wrench in the defense.
She's wonderful,
but she couldn't.
I'm so sorry,
buddy.
So,
I thought a lot about this.
I had one guy,
right,
get her inside the house,
bind her,
and put her into a cell.
Well,
the physical evidence I suggest answers that for us.
Mrs.
Sue had a very distinctive injury on the top of her head.
That injury is consistent with the tip of the large knife that we have every reason to believe was the weapon used to kill her.
I think the evidence suggests that the reason
Betty Dudko heard that keening sound and then it abruptly stops is because he knocked her out.
What is in the tub with
Mrs. Su?
Why don't you look at this picture here.
That's a rug.
It'd be hard to pick up,
you know,
a woman,
a
140-something pound woman,
and put her over your shoulder and carry her.
She's hanging on a rug.
It's not good.
When he threw her in the tub,
he threw in the rug.
that she was right.
But if you look at the bathroom,
other than some drops of blood around the bathroom,
the only really significantly bloody area is right under Mrs.
Su's head when she's laying down on the floor.
So what does that tell you?
That piece of physical evidence tells you she was in the tub when he stabbed her.
She's sitting there in that tub,
tied up,
watching this guy stand over her with a knife,
and he starts stabbing her.
I urge you to put away things and raise your verdict,
evidence,
and come back with a verdict that speaks the truth.
And I told him to stay down through his aisle,
responsibly.
Kelly,
James.
What role,
if any,
did he play in what took place in that home in Davie?
Was he there?
Was he the only one there?
Did he hold the knife?
Did he...
kill this woman?
Does he deserve to be punished as the one who committed the crime?
Or is there someone else out there who either deserves to be punished with him or deserves to be punished instead of him?
Are we putting the right person on trial for the right crime?
That's the mystery of the case of the murder of Jill Sue.
The jury has been deliberating since about 2 o'clock this afternoon and there aren't any signs right now that they'll be wrapping those deliberations up anytime soon.
There are certainly a lot of people here in the hallway along with us waiting to hear what their decision will be.
Know that the jury listened to read back on testimony from the victim's husband and from the victim's son.
So what this is telling me right now,
as we're still waiting for the jury to come back,
is that the defense did a terrific job.
And they raised the questions that the jury wants the answer to.
It's probably some inconsistency that they're trying to compare between the dad and the son.
I'm on the edge.
You know,
it's not a good feeling because
I'm just praying that there's going to be good news.
But it was very heavy on my mind as to what was going to be the verdict today.
In fact,
I thought it was going to be yesterday,
last night.
But it was pushed over to today,
so it's like a waiting game.
We're on the fourth day of deliberations.
We don't know if it's one holdout who believes the defense or if it's a 50-50 split.
There's no way of knowing that until it's over.
But at the very least,
we know that they are taking the questions raised by the defense very,
very seriously.
You can say whatever you want about any jury,
but this one,
you will not be able to say that they rushed.
Let's go out and party.
You ready to proceed?
Yes.
All right,
let's bring him to your end,
please.
Thank you.
Please be seated.
Let the director reflect the presence of the defendant,
Mr.
Rezillas,
his counsel,
his attorney,
and ladies and gentlemen,
the jury.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's my understanding you have reached your verdict,
is that correct?
And
Ms. Hernandez,
are you in the floor person?
All right,
could you pass the verdict form to our bailiff,
please?
Thank you.
Travis,
any poetry for us,
please?
In the circuit court of the 17th Judicial Circuit,
NN4,
Brown County,
Florida,
case number
1412657CF10A, State of Florida v.
Devante Rosillas.
Verdict.
We,
the jury,
find as follows.
As a defendant,
Devante Rosillas,
in this case,
the defendant is guilty of the lesser included crime of manslaughter.
So today we all,
the 7th day of December 2021,
at 4th Ardell,
Broward County,
Florida,
signed by the board person,
Ms.
Hernandez.
Thank you.
Does either the state or the defense wish the jury be polled?
Yes,
sir.
Could you poll the jury,
please?
Ladies and gentlemen,
this means that the clerk,
Mr.
Travis,
is going to ask you a question,
each of you individually,
whether or not the verdict that was read is your verdict.
You should simply answer yes or no.
All right?
Nothing else is required.
Just yes or no if this is your individual verdict.
Mr.
Travis,
will you do?
Ms.
Hernandez,
is this your birthday?
Yeah.
Thank
you.
You need to go back to the jury room and continue with your deliberations.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
Courtroom confusion in a high-profile murder case.
CBS 4's Bobeth Yates has been standing by outside the courthouse in Fort Lauderdale,
waiting for the jury's decision.
Well,
Elliott and Lauren,
it was definitely a wild day.
As you mentioned,
five days of jury deliberation,
and yet again,
the jury could not come to a decision.
For just a few minutes tonight,
it seemed like there was a verdict in this case.
But when that verdict was read aloud,
the judge quickly learned that those jurors
We're not unanimous.
And without a unanimous decision,
the judge said deliberations should keep going.
Here is where we stand.
That jury can come back and find him guilty of that first-degree murder charge,
which can end in life in prison or even the death penalty.
They can come back and find him guilty on lesser charges.
They can acquit him altogether,
or they can even come back and tell the judge that they just can't reach an agreement.
And in an unexpected twist,
the years-long saga...
is not over.
Now they will resume tomorrow morning at 9 a.m.
to begin deliberations once more.
This is one of the most unusual nights for justice in Broward County that I have ever seen.
God,
I ask that you begin to deal with the prosecutors.
I ask that you go before Moochie in any situation,
God.
God,
you are the head.
I ask that you shield him.
God,
that you give him peace.
That you let him know that you're in the midst of the situation,
God.
God,
that there's no one like you,
God.
You can't know what's supposed to get them,
so prosper,
God.
You either did it or you didn't.
What's his name?
He was charged with murder.
And if y'all said y'all don't think he killed him,
then I don't understand what's left.
It's either yes or no.
It ain't no in between.
It's just yes or no.
That's just that.
That's the bottom line on that.
Jury,
you're entering.
Ladies and gentlemen,
thank you.
Please be seated.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I got your jury inquiry form where basically you indicate you are unable to reach unanimous decision on any one charge and its elements.
We,
the jurors,
signed by Ms.
Hernandez.
Is that correct,
ladies and gentlemen?
You're unable to reach an order,
correct?
Yes.
What I would be doing then is just declaring a mistrial and we'll pick up another time with a different jury.
The devil can't talk,
the devil can't do nothing. .
Good,
I'm happy.
I hope the next jury that get picked,
they all agree to not guilty.
Good.
I think I'm going to have me a drink now that my nerves have calmed down a little bit.
We made it through the battle,
but we still got a war.
For the non-believers out there,
I hope you know God is real.
Let that part be known.
I think it's premature to be happy,
but if I were in their shoes,
the most optimistic...
The way to look at this is to say this jury was ready to send him to prison for at least 15 years,
maybe 30.
This jury was ready to do that.
And instead,
we get another chance to convince the next jury he's not guilty.
A jury foreman speaking out about what was going through her mind moments before a high-profile murder case ended in a mistrial.
The jury foreman who chose not to show her face for her safety describing a group of jurors,
some of them biased,
others not following rules.
She said most of the jury was ready to convict Rosilis of at least second degree murder,
but three refused because the defendant is black.
They said,
I don't want to send a young black male to jail for the rest of their life.
They compromised on manslaughter,
but she said she had a pit in her stomach and she changed her mind.
I took a deep breath.
I'm staring at the judge and at the clerk.
And they're just waiting for my verdict of either yes,
I agree or no,
and I just couldn't,
and that's why I said no.
While not the reason for her change of heart,
she said,
she did notice the defense celebrating when that manslaughter verdict was read.
And that was unsettling to me,
you know,
because I knew that it was premeditated.
Returning to the jury room,
she said she was cursed out,
even threatened.
I was threatened to get smacked in my mouth because I said I don't see color.
All I see is a person.
I asked if the outcome would be different if the defendant were white Anglo or a white Hispanic.
Oh,
we would have been done by Friday.
We would have had a verdict on Friday.
How could I agree to manslaughter and say that I'm not going to put a man in jail?
That is actually putting a man in jail if you agree to a person committing manslaughter.
You don't get to walk free if you get manslaughter.
You say,
oh,
well,
you can go home today.
No,
that isn't what that does.
I know that all the other jurors that I've
been in touch with,
we all feel that that was not a representation of,
an accurate representation of what happened.
If you were to look back,
I thought we were being a very proficient jury.
You know,
I think we were being sensitive,
we were taking our time,
we were letting everyone get to speak.
That doesn't scream of an incoherent,
racist,
ranting and raving lunatic room,
you know?
Some of the jurors needed more evidence.
They needed more.
And,
uh...
They weren't just convinced with the DNA.
There was too much DNA and the fingerprints that didn't match the defendant.
That we all felt that there was somebody else.
The question whether the other person did it or not and what was their motive,
I don't know,
but that's why manslaughter became the lowest common denominator.
man.
I just did not want that guy to go home that same day.
I didn't want him to get his car while I'm getting my car and go home and leave that courthouse.
You know what I mean?
So when the deputy comes in,
we're like,
yeah,
we're ready.
But
I had my doubts that it was going to carry through.
And the moment
I heard we're going to poll the jury,
I was holding my breath.
Definitely a weird moment,
because it was so like,
no.
I still,
Holy fuck,
now what?
That's what I was like,
holy fuck,
now what?
What are they going to do with us?
We were done,
and then a couple of us were like,
let's just give it one more chance at the apple.
Let's try one more time.
And if we can do something,
great.
If we can't do something,
fuck it.
And I thought we got over a hump.
And then,
of course,
the same bullshit happened.
She was like,
all young black men are the same.
You know,
they all behave this way.
And,
you know,
like,
I have three sons.
And so,
you know,
like,
my head exploded.
and
I said some things.
I think he actually offered to slap her or something.
And you know,
so it really got ugly.
I got instantly apologized because then I knew that I was dead wrong.
I was dead wrong for allowing it to get to that point.
It's hard to get 12 people to believe in the same.
Because remember,
when you get the evidence,
you have choices.
You can weigh it high.
You can weigh it low or you can ignore it altogether.
Even with witnesses,
you know what I mean?
You can just pick and choose what you want.
And it's going to be hard for 12 people,
in any case,
to decide on anything.
The three of us.
Walked away from it feeling like,
well,
I should just speak for myself.
I walked away from the first trial feeling like a not guilty was possible,
but that we needed to make some changes in order to make that happen.
Presenting the evidence of Nanyao and Justin's involvement in a more aggressive way was our best shot in doing that.
A.
Well,
the second trial of a man accused of a gruesome murder has started.
The case has taken many turns,
the latest of which was a mistrial.
Well,
Jackie,
here we go again,
and it's almost three months to the day that that mistrial was declared the first time around.
And a new jury now has been seated for his retrial.
Prosecutors argue Rizul's DNA was found in the home.
The defense claims someone else did it.
Opening statements have just started in the retrial of Deontay Rezillas,
and we can already see a difference in strategy from the defense.
Did the husband or the son have a role in the death of Jill Sue?
We'll be right back.
Cold,
cold eyes upon me they stare People all around me and they're all in fear
They don't seem to want me,
but they won't admit To be some kind of creature if they haven't been
Having a hard time in this crazy town
Having a hard time
Betty Dutko?
To the extent that Betty Dutko saw anything,
the timing of when she saw it is important.
She testifies that it happened sometime after 12.
We don't have any police report from a police officer.
We don't know who the police officer is that she talked to while on scene.
The first mention that we have of it from any law enforcement officer is from
Detective Williams,
while Detective Williams is in the interview room with Nan Yao.
I'm not sure if you talked to Betty,
Dr.
Goh?
Yes,
we spoke to her.
Betty,
she said she saw somebody,
something,
dragging something in.
And at the time,
it's about what?
What time you said?
What she said,
what,
12?
No,
she said about 11,
Detective Williams tells Nan Yao that...
Betty Dutko saw what she saw at 11.15.
You then see Nanyao try to maneuver that conversation to push it to later.
At the time the car is gone,
right?
She says no car there in the front.
One of the other detectives talked to her.
Yeah.
Yeah,
because when she's talking to the detective,
I heard that.
And I asked her,
did you see any car in the window up?
And she says,
no car.
That's mean that I have to have left before that.
But that's the first evidence that we have of when that conversation happened.
But
Detective Williams never goes to talk to her until
November 17,
2014,
over two months later.
He goes,
he has a very
perfunctory conversation with her in which now
Betty Ducko is saying that it happened sometime afternoon.
And isn't it true that the information you had at that time was that Ms.
Ducko had seen that at 11 15 a.m.
Protection.
A.
Hearsay and B.
Some facts not in evidence.
Sustained.
Generally the rule is that you can't testify to what other people have told you.
We know that,
but sometimes,
not all the time,
we can articulate questions so that the jury at least hears the question and they know that there's something out there that they're not getting to see.
But if
Betty saw what she saw at 1115,
Danielle was home during that.
There was no particular reason why you were checking the cameras in your home on September 8,
2014,
right?
I can check anytime I want.
And when you turn it on,
you just happen to see somebody on this camera,
correct?
Correct.
You called your son at 12 a.m.
and you first asked him if he was the one that was on that camera,
correct?
That's correct.
because
Because he had previously,
while you were on vacation,
covered his face.
That's correct,
yeah.
You don't have any workers that come to your house and cover their face,
correct?
Correct.
And the person that you testified earlier,
you thought was a man,
correct?
That's correct.
In your house,
while your wife is sleeping,
correct?
That's correct.
And you are only 10 minutes away,
correct?
Correct.
And you sent your son,
who at that time was 20,
to go to the house and check on that suspicious figure,
correct?
That's correct.
It just didn't make sense that he saw this suspicious figure who has a mask on,
and he would send the only child,
his youngest child,
the only child that lives with him,
over to check in.
into the suspicious figure.
But you saw the person walk over towards the direction of that second drop cam,
the one that had just finished the recording subscription,
correct?
That's correct.
You testified when you were talking to the state that your intent was to never pay to have recordings for that camera,
correct?
That's correct.
But you told the police that your intent was actually to pay for a subscription service that would record what was going on in your home.
No.
How do you say that?
And you're sure about that?
I'm sure about that.
You may approach.
So I asked people,
I got two cameras.
And one of them I look at in my living room and basically I have a video recording all the time.
I pay for that.
And I also,
with this second camera I bought for this house,
my intention is that after the initial 14 days expire,
I was going to go ahead and purchase it anyway.
It does not say purchase recording.
Do you have enough time to look at it?
Yeah.
He's changed stories on what happened with the recordings,
with the camera,
and why.
If the truth is the truth,
it shouldn't change.
Why does it change for him after all this time?
So that's why we try to bring out to the jury.
After you went back home,
your son still stayed living with you,
is that right?
Yes,
correct.
And when did he move?
He moved out with all the neighbors.
When he moved out,
was there a conflict?
Between him and your second wife,
objection loans.
In May 2015,
this,
like,
20-something-year-old girl starts working in his department.
He starts dating her shortly after that,
a year and two months after his wife's death.
And then he marries her in 2017.
She wasn't even hired by your daughter until 2015,
right?
That's correct.
Didn't know this woman when Mrs.
Hsu died in 2014.
No,
I didn't know her.
Alright,
how long did it take you to get here?
10 to 15 minutes.
What did you find when you got here?
Police over and my property was caught with yellow tape.
And I saw Justin sitting around somewhere.
I tried to approach him.
The police told me I can't get near to him.
I was asked to sit down.
So I sat on the lawn.
And I saw the girl being rolled out.
You sound like...
Stretcher.
Being rolled out from the front door.
And there's a body there,
and cover the face with blanket.
I start to yell at the medical personnel.
I told them,
please revive her.
Please.
She cannot be dead.
Do something.
And they just shook their head.
And I just lost it.
Her body was never removed by paramedics.
Never.
She was dead.
He wasn't left on scene until 740.
Williams testified that he was transported to the police station before any of this.
So when did this happen,
this revive her,
revive her of the Gertie?
It didn't.
Never.
He knows that there is a suggestion that he is involved in the murder.
I mean,
we said that in our opening statement.
And so anything that he can do to show the jury how much he loved Jill and how devastating this was cuts against that,
right?
Could that be why he told the jury that?
Of course.
But of course,
we know that he was 100%
lying about seeing her body and all of that.
And Ayadi can use it.
We're closing and we can show that to the jury.
Good afternoon,
we're Justin Su.
Come up here please,
this is our witness stand.
Justin testifies he picks up his parents from the airport and then he's home with them all night long.
You said that you picked up your parents from the airport,
correct?
Correct.
You brought them home?
Correct?
Correct.
And then you were with them the entire night,
correct?
Yes.
But then we also have several texts between Justin and his friend Corey later on that evening about meeting up for the purpose of smoke some kind of marijuana.
But it's something called dabs.
I don't know what it is.
So we felt that that directly refuted
Justin saying he never left the house the night before.
Whether him leaving the house the night before,
you know,
has anything to do with what happened the next morning,
we don't know.
There's no way for us to know.
But again,
it very much shows that
Justin lied about another part of this,
another part of this case.
But then also,
there was a lot of focus about Justin lying about where he went,
which is important.
But
I was more interested in why he left the house to begin with,
because
I don't accept his reasoning.
for leaving the house at 944.
I am very interested in what happens between 915 and 944.
You're at home,
correct?
Yes.
Your dad is at home,
correct?
Yes.
There is a period between 915 and 944 in which all three of them are home.
We have no idea what happens during that time.
And finally I wake up at about 9,
9,
910 or something like that.
You got up and she was still in bed.
She was asleep.
She was totally asleep.
When's the last time you saw your mom?
This morning,
around probably like
9.45 right before I left.
I said,
hey,
do you want to work?
She was just reading a book in the living room the last time I saw her.
Something causes Justin to leave at 9.44 to get away from the house and he essentially goes and he sits in his car for two hours.
I mean,
the cause was...
I wanted it to appear that I was working.
That was the cause.
I left the house.
What?
Is that what you want,
right?
A fight between his parents would be a reason for him to want to leave.
Jill being killed then would be a reason for him to leave.
You know,
dad saying,
go,
leave the house,
and then whatever dad does in the next two hours.
You know,
I don't know.
But.
He is a emotional person.
And so to me,
if he was going through some sort of emotional crisis between 944 and 1218,
he's not going to go see people.
He's going to go,
and he's going to sit in his car,
and he's going to be with himself in his car.
You left your home at 944 AM leaving your dad and your mom on the lawn.
So go sit in an empty car and wear on a pelvic.
Actually,
that's the answer.
Steve.
Something happened between that time period that,
again,
caused Justin to want to leave the house.
But then also,
it was really important for me to emphasize that what he did upon finding his mom,
it never,
ever made any sense.
This line here goes around the top of the tongue.
Is that how high the water level was when you were there?
I think so.
For Justin to have lifted his mother,
who weighed more than him,
out of the tub,
out of this tub that is filled to the brink,
there would have been a mess.
I mean,
it would have been a mess of bloody water all over the floor.
And yet,
this floor was bone dry.
I mean,
it wasn't just there was
A little bit of water.
There was no water at all.
You attempted to do CPR on your mom.
Yeah.
Did you do that before or after you called the vet?
I did that as soon as I took my mom out of the tub.
He calls 911 after he's taken her out of the tub,
after he's done CPR,
after he's supposedly done mouth-to-mouth.
That process,
all of that process,
necessarily would have shown.
that she was tied up and that she had all of these stab wounds.
But when he calls 911,
he says she committed suicide.
The jury can see that there is no way that he could not have known that his mom was murdered before he called 911.
During this time,
you're walking through multiple parts of the home,
correct?
Yes.
And again,
you didn't stop to put shoes on at any point,
correct?
Correct.
But there are no bloody footprints.
There's no footprints at all.
There's no blood on the front door,
on the sliding glass door.
You have touched the sliding door,
which means you would have blood on the sliding door handle of your mom.
Yes.
And you would have blood on the lock on the front door of your mom's?
Do you agree with me?
Yes,
I agree with you.
That should be there.
Right.
And if there isn't,
what does that mean?
And so the physical evidence simply doesn't support Justin's story of removing his mom from the tub.
It's not enough that the defense has to attack Nanyau and Justin and make it appear that they're responsible for this crime.
They need to discredit the DNA evidence.
It is the most important piece of evidence linking Deonte Rosillas to the crime scene.
I mean,
that's a good point.
Good thinking.
The Broward Sheriff's Office has a crime lab that tests for DNA,
correct?
Correct.
And yet in this case,
you directed that those swabs be sent to this...
place in tampa correct the lab the florida department of law reports fdlu lab what happened with these swabs is very very very unusual i've never seen a case where law
enforcement sent swabs out of broward county so early in an investigation the few times where we see
DNA being sent to a specialized lab is when it's already been analyzed here in Broward County and there needs some sort of specialization in the analysis.
Then it's your testimony that on September
11th, the following day,
you got another call from somebody at FDLE and said,
actually,
we're not going to take it,
correct?
Detective Williams says,
I called FDLE,
and FDLE told me that they could do it.
Then he says,
the next day,
FDLE calls me and tells me,
oops,
sorry,
actually,
we can't do it.
And
FDLE sends the 12 back to you,
correct?
Correct.
Now,
instead of trying to get people to believe that this is not,
you know,
that the identification with Deontay is an error.
Now we're trying to get people to believe that the identification with Deonte is not a mistake,
it's sabotage.
There are no initials over the evidence tape for the packages themselves.
We know that those boxes are,
that,
you know,
boxes that these swabs come in.
Every law enforcement agency everywhere has those same boxes.
And so,
you know,
it's important for the jury to see that.
Like,
this is the most important evidence.
that the state has against Deontay.
And from September 10th to September 12th,
they are,
again,
inexplicably and very,
very unusually sent out of the county.
And we certainly don't know what was happening to those swabs in the meantime.
And then miraculously,
five days later,
Deontay's DNA shows up on the street.
We ain't got much.
Support,
support,
support.
Not guilty.
If you had a message for Dayante,
what would it be?
It would be a lot,
but to sum it up,
you will win.
That's it.
You will win.
Good morning ma'am.
You look very nice.
For seven and a half years,
Mr.
Resilis has been locked up for 23 hours a day.
Out for only one hour is his only time for human interaction if someone isn't involved.
For one hour a day,
for seven and a half years,
he has had to wait until this day.
So you get to decide if for seven and a half years,
the state has done everything that they could to prove to you that he committed this murder beyond the exclusion of every reasonable doubt.
They have to do that.
They had seven and a half years to bring you all the evidence,
to test everything that they needed to test,
to bring you witnesses,
to bring you concrete,
credible proof that he killed Josue.
And seven and a half years they wasted because they did not do that.
What they show you here today is not.
in any way prove that Deyante killed Jill soon.
At all.
I start to feel like
I told them,
please revive her.
Please.
She cannot be dead.
Do something.
And they just shook their heads.
The rest of the memory,
it just felt like they had totally lost any sense of power.
He just said he saw her body under the cover.
And he's begging,
revive her,
please revive her,
my wife.
And they look at him and nod their head no,
and they take the body,
and then he gets taken to the police or department.
And that's pretty powerful,
right?
You have an image of a distraught husband seeing that.
Is it true?
It's not true.
Because what do we know?
That body was picked up at 7.40
PM. He's already in the police department.
His interview had already started.
So why is he saying that?
It's a complete lie.
That never happens.
Very dramatically,
we get that clip of Dr.
Hsu at the end saying that when he saw the EMS people coming out with a gurney and a body bag,
he assumed that was his wife's body on there and he yelled at them,
revived them,
do something,
and they shook their head no.
How did he know what was on that bottom packet?
How did he know that the body stays there when there's something they can do for the body until the medical examiner arrives?
That was the impression that he got.
And then,
how do they explain the way they're doing?
The only attack that she can do on the DNA is by saying that it went to FDLE.
Okay,
let's analyze it.
The implication to counsel's argument would be that the FDLE guys decide,
hmm.
David Petty suspects the son.
So let's really throw a monkey wrench in their investigation.
Let's plant somebody's DNA in this stuff.
But we're not going to put his DNA on all the items.
We're going to put his DNA on two of the items.
And on one of the items,
we're just going to put a little bit of the egg.
Just enough so that now they can't detect it.
But in 2017,
2018,
2019,
when they get more sophisticated testing and equipment,
then they'll be able to detect it.
That's the argument,
people.
If you take it to its logical conclusion,
that's the argument.
You've got to remember the common sense.
The science puts him there.
The science puts his hands on a weapon.
The science puts his hands on an item that tied Mrs.
Sobot.
But there's also a possibility,
you can infer from the evidence,
he wasn't alone.
Maybe when Dr.
Sue said,
and look white to me,
maybe there was a white guy with him.
Maybe.
We don't know.
But you know what we do know?
There being another white woman,
it's not excusing.
Does not exonerate him,
does not relieve him of responsibility in any way,
shape,
or form.
Well,
we finally learned,
you know,
she conceded.
Well,
maybe there was somebody else.
Maybe there was a white person.
But she has to.
No,
I know,
but she hasn't.
But at least I had brought it up that I was like...
Well,
but she realized,
obviously,
in the first trial that didn't go so well for her.
For deliberations,
like,
we have to all be
Yeah,
because if we get a question,
Right,
that's what I was thinking,
but she said something when we were leaving.
Can I wear my free Moochie t-shirt?
Yes.
I think they're gonna have a verdict Thursday.
Of not guilty.
Yes.
And if it's not guilty,
I'm going to be bawling crying.
This cannot be guilty of first-degree murder.
It cannot.
I received a jury inquiry form.
It says request to view evidence,
then it goes testimonies.
Elijah Shaw,
Petro
Cingeli, Officer Badakis,
Paul Williams,
Rebecca McDougal,
Paul Ledesma,
Justin Su,
Dr.
Su.
There is absolutely no chance that we have the wrong guy.
And when you know everything else that you need to know about this young man,
you would have no doubt.
Unfortunately,
the jury doesn't know everything about him.
But if they did,
they would not be out there struggling like they are now.
What exactly are you referring to?
I'm referring about the fact that he commits burglaries continuously that match the exact same manner of this burglary.
Those are not coincidences.
Those are things that he has done and that are very,
very consistent with what he did here.
We do not have the wrong guy.
The jury doesn't know this,
so they may get it wrong,
but we didn't get it wrong.
I'm sorry,
did I just get a little too passionate there?
No,
you're all right.
It's just that the idea,
the idea that someone who could just,
I'm sorry,
but someone who could just kill somebody who's sleeping in their house for no reason other than they don't want to get caught is so offensive,
so wrong.
It could have been anybody.
He burns every day.
But that's not the issue.
So we'll see.
But I am not hopeful right now.
I think Mr.
Brooks decided that this young man could be him.
And that he is,
you know,
it's the same situation.
I don't think it's even a phone call.
It's going to be a piece of cake.
He wrote us notes and we got those notes about travel.
What are you asking me to do for this?
And they come up on the bird,
come on y'all.
I spoke to Dr.
Su and he's really hugging his legs and he's not actually doing it.
Alright,
just bring the jury.
Thank you,
please be seated.
Let the record once again reflect the defendant,
the defendant,
the counsel,
and the assistant state attorney,
as well as the lady governor of Nigeria.
Ladies and gentlemen,
it's my understanding you have reached a verdict,
is that correct?
Yes,
sir.
Mr.
Brooks,
do you have paperwork there?
He's a poor person.
Yes,
sir.
Thanks,
Mitch.
I'll go over there.
Can you publish the report,
please?
In the circuit corridor,
the 17th judicial survey in and for Broward County Corridor,
the case number 12657,
conceded that the state of Florida versus the state of Iowa.
And so it was referred to.
We did jury find as follows.
the defendant is guilty of murder in a first degree as charged in the indictment so say we all this
18th day of march
2022 at fort robert county florida and it's signed by the court process and who is the foreperson
Mr.
Brooks.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
at this time,
I'm going to excuse you today.
We don't have a penalty phase set up yet.
My thought is to set this for status sometime next week and find out.
when we'd be able to do the second phase of the trial.
What I'd like to do is if we could discuss that sometime next week,
give everybody a chance to think about it and discuss that next week.
Let's go.
Come on,
let's go.
Then we'll have a penalty.
We're gonna be back April 1st to set that.
But before then,
we're gonna have a meeting with the state attorney to see if we can avoid that.
Nothing's really,
really taken down.
Investing keep on going over this here.
And got a major part in this here.
I swear for God,
not just on the truth.
I'm out.
Listen,
again,
listen,
it's not the end of the fight.
It's not,
it don't stop here.
He's gonna have,
you know,
we have to deal with second phase,
obviously.
So you mean to tell me y'all,
they saying first degree,
that's the death penalty.
They gonna kill my child for something that daddy did?
Here's what I will say.
Lord Jesus.
Is that a potential sentence?
Yeah.
But we're going to try like hell to talk to them beforehand.
We're going to still be fighting.
Okay.
It's not over.
All right?
Okay.
Y'all will talk to Deontay before I do.
Tell him I love him.
Keep his head up.
And God won't steal Pram because we know
God going to open up new doors.
I was in contact with Dr.
Su.
I was in contact right before the verdict and immediately I texted him and let him know and he is relieved.
You know everyone wants there to be closure.
Everyone wants to be able to move on.
No one will ever forget Mrs.
Su but they want to be able to move on and this hopefully will give them that sense of closure that they so desperately needed.
I still don't really fully know.
I don't.
I was,
I ended up being fine with the guilty part,
yeah.
But the thing was,
there's a thing called principle.
Whereas if you were there and assisted the person who did it in any way,
you're treated as the person who did it.
And.
We had nobody to interpret that for us.
We had to do it ourselves.
And we all was like,
well,
we don't believe that he did it,
but the
DNA says he's there to the Septillion.
So by what they gave us to determine this,
that would technically make him guilty.
We got to the point where like,
okay,
this is what it is.
And then like when we read the principle,
it was like,
well,
why are we even here?
It just makes a lot of stuff moot.
And it's like a math equation that you can't check,
you know?
It's like you solve this problem,
but you can't check to see if you made the right equation.
You can't check your work.
Damn,
did I do right?
Because here's the thing is,
if I failed,
that means that that person's killer is still out there.
You know,
and there was technically no justice served for this woman.
New for you at noon,
prosecutors will no longer be seeking the death penalty for a man convicted of murdering a woman in her Davie home in 2014.
Yeah,
the announcement was made at a hearing this morning for Deonte Rosillas,
who was found guilty last month of killing that mother in Davie.
Immediately after the conviction,
both
Ms. Schneider and Ms.
McGuire came up to us at the defense table and suggested,
they themselves suggested that we reach out to
Harold Pryor,
the state attorney.
to talk about waiving the death penalty.
I think that they,
having been through that second trial,
they knew that a death sentence was very,
very unlikely.
I mean,
the state ended up conceding that there could have been or very well was another person,
and we,
you know,
we'll get,
if we ever catch that person,
we'll deal with that person at that time,
and that was a big concession.
I believe is what allowed them ultimately to get their conviction,
but on the flip side of that,
we believe very firmly that there was no way that all 12 jurors were convinced,
beyond all reasonable doubt,
that Deontay actually murdered Jill.
And because of that,
we didn't think that they were going to vote for the death penalty.
You know,
I think it became obvious that this was not a death penalty case.
I don't think this person is a normal person.
He's a psychopath.
A psychopath like that,
I don't mind seeing them on the table with a lethal injection.
In fact,
I already told my family that if that happened,
I would probably go see it as a witness.
But oh well,
I have to respect Jill's wish.
I know her very well.
She is a very,
very merciful person.
She is not a vengeance person.
Besides,
she would not want to make a decision resulting in somebody's death.
That's not her.
We all three of us all agree with that one.
So with that,
that's our primary reason to say,
OK,
let's go with the life in prison.
We don't care.
We need to honor what she would think,
she would feel.
That's more important than anything else.
That allow us to put this chapter across this book and then move on with our life.
I just can't be,
you know,
stagnant about the situation.
I got to keep moving forward and trying to do what's right.
So
I'm trying to raise a little money.
Somebody may put $50 out of their paycheck,
$100 here.
You know,
we getting money,
saving it,
and just going to invest and try to get them free.
We looking for different lawyers.
Nobody around here can rest if we're just able to rest free outside of that system right there in its own bed.
The job is not done yet.
Got to keep going.
The job is not done.
Huh?
Come on,
leave it alone.
I know it's broke.
The whole system broke,
Fanny,
but we gonna fix it.
Every kid wants the same things.
They want to be loved.
They want to have whatever food they want.
They want to have nice clothes.
They want to have nice things.
I mean,
we all have the same wants and desires.
And I think that there are some children who sadly grow up in circumstances where they really don't see a way for them to attain those things.
In a pro-social way,
in an acceptable way.
So they turn to crime for them.
I don't think it's just a matter of someone being born evil,
you know.
I think that there are a lot of societal things that contribute to the behavior.
But the vast majority of kids who do live under those circumstances don't kill people.
So just because there are factors that contribute to it,
do not excuse the behavior.
We spent so many hours together,
so much time getting to know him as a person,
helping him when there's difficulty in the jail and helping us address his concerns.
That's what you do with your friends.
You listen to their grievances,
you try to help them out,
you look out for them.
I do think that we would consider him like a friend.
He was trying to make us feel better when the conviction came down,
like,
you know.
Having us,
you know,
realize that how grateful he was for us fighting for him.
A couple weeks ago,
we all...
I met with him in the jail while we were still going through the death penalty waiver process.
And at the end,
he said,
you know,
before we're done,
I just want to say thank you.
And
I spoke for a good,
you know,
10 minutes talking to us.
He was crying.
We were crying.
And I think that that doesn't usually happen.
Mike wasn't crying.
Yes,
no harm.
Oh,
good.
Is Deontay Rezillis simply a charmer?
Is he just somebody who can gather people to his cause because of his charisma?
Or is he a killer who manipulates those...
who he befriends in order to cover up the crime that he committed.
That's the central question in this case.
We are here on the set of
Gucci's video R.I.P.
It's not for just entertainment,
you know,
it's to bring about awareness to his situation along with a lot of people who's in his situation.
A way to give them a voice as well.
In the back of my mind,
I know that this is not the end.
And I really hope he knows that,
you know.
So this is just an example of how we're still going to put in that effort to keep his name alive.
We see cases a few times a year,
and they probably happen more than that.
Somebody went to jail for
18 years for a murder they didn't commit.
30 years.
For a murder they didn't commit.
How many guys are in there for stuff they didn't do?
Once you put these almost legal malpractice on top of a general mistrust,
it creates this big wall to where you have a tough time trusting anything.
In the case of Deontay,
DNA evidence is tough to fight.
But if you have a tremendous skepticism about the whole system,
as I'm sure his family does,
then you think they're just trying to stick it to another young black man.
They say there's a lot of cynicism,
there's a lot of mistrust,
and it doesn't help anybody.
But exactly how do you expect us to feel when this happens time after time?
I ain't slept since Friday.
You hear me?
I been fucking crying,
drinking,
I'm just gonna tell you the bloody ass wrong truth.
This shit is hurtful.
We had to put our families through this situation because of somebody's prior past,
and judge them,
and just sit there and throw a book at somebody and say that they committed this crime and he did not do it.
I would not be here.
You understand me?
The state asked if we were interested in resolving the other cases.
Obviously we were because you know we're hopeful that Deonte gets an appeal so not spend the rest of his life in prison.
But these other cases if we try them and we don't win he can get
Life sentences on some of the pending cases or the ones that don't have a maximum of life,
they can be stacked or he can be incarcerated to what would be the equivalent of the rest of his life.
The deal that we made gives him hope,
right?
And so he's going to do
15 years on all of those other cases.
He'll do 85%
of whatever's left.
So he'll be done with those cases in eight and a years or so and then
Which means that if the appeal is successful,
then he has hope of getting out.
Let's get back on the record please.
This is in the state of Florida versus
Deonte Rosales.
So,
council,
we're here on the sentencing on the first three murder.
And you want to have some statements by the witnesses?
Yes,
sir.
May I call?
Good afternoon,
sir.
Jill is the kind of person who could help you.
Instead you kill her.
No,
you did not just kill her.
you didn't.
You killed her and called blood.
Like a psychopath.
I understand you've been doing,
breaking people's hearts since you were like what,
14 years?
Every time you get arrested,
instead of saying,
I better quit,
you would think about some clever scheme to see if it can improve your chance of not being caught the next time.
So you have a plan before you come to my house.
You say,
if some homeowner says,
this is what I would do,
what did you do?
You stopped on more than 25 clients.
Why?
Because you try to make it look like the murder was happening in rage.
Meaning that somebody had to know her and was very mad at her,
kill her.
Naturally,
this has to be family member.
You put hot water in the bathtub.
Because you know,
forensic estimate of death time is based on body temperature.
If you keep the body warm,
you cannot estimate that well.
Until somebody lift the body out,
the cooling starts from that point.
Meaning that it can implicate the person who lift the body out.
In this case,
it's why my son tested.
He almost succeeded.
If it's not for DNA evidence,
he almost succeeded.
Throughout history,
we depict evil as the one with the red face,
blood-shedded eyes,
phone with blood dripping out from the mouth.
No,
we are all wrong.
We are all wrong.
The real evil looks like that.
That is the face of evil sitting there.
An evil like you should not allow to be wrong amongst us.
After this,
today,
young DeRizio,
I'm going to erase you from my memory.
In my mind,
you are a son of Rata.
You do not exist.
And we are going to make sure we live happily for the rest of our life while you rot in jail.
You can't
describe how what that does to a human being.
what that does to see the most beloved person in your whole entire life be treated like that.
It is mind-breaking.
And it really frustrates me because I want to be the stronger person and move on with my life.
But I know for a fact that until the day I die,
it's going to affect me from what I witnessed and went through.
And that's just one aspect of it.
And here's the other aspect that's in this courtroom right now.
Your whole entourage of people that you have.
It really affects me when you're taking the air and wind out of the sail of other people.
Okay,
they could,
those people out there,
they could be using their energy to go help people in Buffalo,
New York.
You know,
they could be using their energy elsewhere,
but no,
they're using their energy to support a murderer.
George Floyd,
BLM,
all those,
taking all those people away from it.
And on that road...
Deontay,
to whether picking metal or pine is going to be your last decision you're going to make,
have fun watching everyone you know that you think love you and that love you slowly go on with their lives and just forget about who you were.
You slowly become nothing and you're going to be very lonely in a very tiny spot for the rest of your life.
It doesn't make me sleep better at night,
but just know that that's a fact.
Just like the fact that you murdered my mother,
that's a fact that that's what the rest of your life is gonna look like.
Thank you.
Judge,
I have a question about the decision on Artesha.
That's fine.
Mr.
Rizzo,
you have a seat.
You have a seat.
I'm going to swear again,
but you can be seated.
You solemnly swear or affirm the testimony you're about to give in this court to be the truth,
the whole truth,
and nothing but the truth?
Yes,
I do.
Thank you,
sir.
You put your hand down.
Tell me your true and lawful name.
My true and lawful name is Deontay Rosettis.
Just spell your last name for the court reporter,
please.
R-E-S-T-I-L-E-S.
Thank you.
I don't mean to come off combative.
Oppositely placed,
I would feel the same way.
If somebody was to take my mom from me,
I would feel those same feelings.
If somebody took my wife from me,
But it's just hard for me to cradle in my soul in a sense when what I'm being accused of is beyond me.
And then you say,
Justin,
People will leave me one by one.
Nobody's obligated to stay with me along my journey.
Once what I've said is concluded,
everybody in this room will walk out,
go through that door and go on with their life.
You guys are absolutely correct.
I will leave,
go through that side door and be transported to prison.
But any day,
at any hour,
any decade,
if it will provide you guys with the soldiers,
they can hook me up to a polygraph test at any given time,
ask me any question they wish,
and my answer will remain the same.
I did not kill Mr.
Sue,
and that's all I have to say.
And to my family.
I love y'all.
I don't want y'all.
Don't cry for me.
No matter what I gotta go through,
I'm gonna get through it.
It doesn't bother me.
It's not gonna bother me.
It's just a small bump in the road.
I'll continue on in my fight,
but just do tell my daughter for me.
Just letting you know I love her and y'all don't gotta cry for me.
I'll be fine.
And to my attorneys,
I want to tell you guys,
I really appreciate it.
Grateful,
I'm thankful.
I've gone through this process.
You guys became sort of family figures to me.
And I've had this conversation with you guys multiple times.
But
I thank you guys for everything.
And though my tears fall,
I'll be all right.
Thank you.
Yes,
sir.
House of Dwayne,
any else before ground sense regarding this case?
No,
sir.
Mr.
Brazils,
the jury having found you guilty of murder in first degree is charged in the indictment under case number 14-12657 CF10A.
The court now finds you guilty,
adjudicates you guilty,
and sentences you to life in prison.